Thank you.
谢谢。
¶¶
¶¶
Satsang with Mooji
与Mooji一起坐着
Thank you.
谢谢。
All right.
好的。
Welcome back to the Ethereum Protocol Fellowship Study Group.
欢迎回到以太坊协议研究小组。
We are here on week nine, only a couple weeks left.
我们在第九周就在这里，还剩几周。
And today we are here with Pari Tosh from EF DevOps,
今天，我们与EF Devops的Pari Tosh在一起，
who is going to be talking about some test nets and prototyping and all sorts of fun stuff.
谁会谈论一些测试网，原型制作以及各种有趣的东西。
So I'll go ahead and let Mario introduce Pari a little bit more deeper here,
因此，我将继续前进，让Mario在这里介绍Pari更深一些，
and we'll get started.
我们将开始。
Thanks for being here, Pari.
感谢您在这里，Pari。
Hey, Pari.
嘿，帕里。
it's amazing to have charters here because uh we already had a presentation by mario before
在这里有宪章真是太神奇了，因为嗯，我们之前已经在马里奥演讲了
uh montague um we've been talking about testing and i mentioned it is important in testing the
UH Montague UM我们一直在谈论测试，我提到这对于测试很重要
merge and so on but uh the merch also would not happen without pari and uh ef devops or
合并等等，但是如果没有pari和uh ef devops或
as they became during the merge actually the panda ops uh team working on uh testing tooling
当它们在合并中实际上是熊猫OPS UH团队从事UH测试工具
uh on prototyping tooling on uh these devs tools which not just uh enable the thing itself but
UH上的原型工具在这些开发工具上，不仅是启用事物本身，还可以
making it easier for developers to uh run uh local or public business uh shadow forks and uh and they
使开发人员更容易运行UH本地或公共业务UH Shadow Forks and UH，他们
uh and and they develop uh some tools which can help you to monitor even your own nodes and uh
嗯，他们开发了一些工具，可以帮助您监视自己的节点和嗯
that's what this is so lots of interesting stuff uh the panda albums became a powerhouse of these
这就是很多有趣的东西
things and uh and papari is the it's kind of the face of uh breaking the test nets and creating
事情和乌巴里和爸爸是UH打破测试网并创建的一种面孔
new ones uh ethereum so it's it's really great to have you here um i think we can we can get
新的，嗯
into it uh get the presentation ready so so the stage is yours yeah it's a temporary perfect
进入它准备演示文稿，所以舞台是您的，是的，这是一个暂时的完美
thank you guys for having me again um so today i'm going to be talking about uh testing and
谢谢你们再次拥有我，所以今天我要谈论UH测试和
prototyping Ethereum upgrades, which might be an interesting topic for a lot of you, because
原型以太坊升级，这对你们中的许多人来说可能是一个有趣的话题，因为
I'm assuming through the protocol studies, once you're done with this, you would want to
我假设通过协议研究，一旦完成，您将想
try out making changes to Ethereum. And the nicest part is because everything is open source,
尝试更改以太坊。最好的部分是因为一切都是开源的，
you can run it yourself. And it might just, there's quite a bit of a learning curve in
您可以自己运行。可能只是，有很多学习曲线
running a fresh network where you're not ruining anything, or you're not breaking someone's system.
运行一个新的网络，您不会破坏任何东西，或者您不会破坏某人的系统。
So we've been trying to make that easier. We've been trying to make the concept of prototyping easier.
因此，我们一直在努力使它更容易。我们一直在尝试使原型制作的概念更加容易。
And through that, we've also built a lot of new testing tools.
通过此，我们还构建了许多新的测试工具。
So I'm going to introduce a couple of those concepts to you today.
因此，我今天将向您介绍一些这些概念。
So the first thing I want to just set the stage, right?
因此，我想只是设置舞台的第一件事，对吗？
Ethereum has something like 20 plus client combinations.
以太坊具有大约20多个客户组合。
There's more every week, every month.
每个月每周都有更多。
um we're recently going to start um onboarding the lambda class elixir client we worked on
嗯，我们最近将开始登上我们工作的lambda类长辈客户端
onboarding the grandin client over the last month so it feels like the number of combinations and
上个月登上Grandin客户的登机，这感觉就像组合的数量和
this matrix keeps increasing because we try to test each and every el with each and every cl
此矩阵不断增加，因为我们尝试用每一个CL测试每个EL
so even having like one new client adds 10 new systems for 10 new columns in the matrix matrix
因此，即使拥有一个新客户端也添加了10个新系统，用于矩阵矩阵中的10列新列
for us debugging them also gets really difficult as you can imagine you kind of have to get a bit
对于我们来说，调试它们也变得非常困难，因为您可以想象您必须有点
into each and every you have to get in the intricacy of each and every EL and CL
进入每个人都必须进入每个EL和CL的复杂性
and we had to figure out how to reliably test all of these things it didn't help if one person ran
我们必须弄清楚如何可靠地测试所有这些事情，如果一个人跑了
a script on one machine and then this says trust me it works up until the merge I think we mostly
一台机器上的脚本，然后说相信我，它一直在努力，直到合并我认为我们主要是
just did single client testing. So you would test Geth in itself, you would test Nethermind
只是进行了单个客户端测试。因此，您会本身测试Geth，您将测试Nethermind
in itself, and maybe there were one or two test suites where you would test Geth and
本身，也许有一两个测试套件，您将在这里测试Geth和
Nethermind together, but not that many. So over the last year or two years, we've been
nethermind在一起，但没有那么多。所以在过去的两年或两年中，我们已经去过
focusing a lot on getting this interop level testing. So you have all of these clients
专注于进行此次级别测试。因此，您拥有所有这些客户
spinning up and ensuring that they're all working equally well, irrespective of if they're
旋转并确保它们的运作良好，无论是否
majority client or not um and another thing is that every upgrade is going to inherit some of
多数客户端还是不是um，另一件事是每个升级都将继承一些
this complexity so we're trying to build something such as that is a bit expandable so if you build
这种复杂性，因此我们试图构建诸如此类的东西有些扩展，因此，如果您构建
it once you can use it for the next few upgrades we don't want to re-envision the testing stack
它一旦您可以在接下来的几个升级中使用它，我们就不想重新启动测试堆栈
for each and every upgrade that just adds a lot of toil adds a lot of time so we're trying to keep
对于每次增加劳动的升级，都会增加很多时间，因此我们正在尝试保留
things as generic as possible and with anyone who's worked with software in the past that can
尽可能通用的事情以及过去使用软件的任何人都可以
be very hard because we don't even know what's coming on ethereum um so how are you generalizing
要非常困难，因为我们甚至都不知道以太坊的会发生什么，所以您如何推广
something without knowing it right and i'll go a bit into how we've attempted to tackle the problem
不知道正确的东西，我将介绍一下我们如何试图解决问题的方法
at least and competences for ELs and CLs are quite separate so um different teams look build
至少ELS和CLS的能力是非常分开的，所以不同的团队看起来建立
different clients there's not that many people who have an overlap of the entire stack so we try
不同的客户没有多少人对整个堆栈有重叠，所以我们尝试
to separate testing in such a way that it's also conducive to it. So we first try to figure out,
分开测试的方式也有利于它。所以我们首先尝试弄清楚，
is this a CL issue? Is this an EL issue? Then we try to escalate in those directions. So
这是CL问题吗？这是一个问题吗？然后，我们尝试升级这些方向。所以
it's kind of pointless if you escalate every CL bug to all the EL devs, that's just how you get
如果您将每个CL错误升级到所有El Devs，那就是您获得的方式，这是毫无意义的
people ignoring bugs. So the next kind of step of the introduction is a really big part of our
人们忽略错误。因此，引言的下一个步骤是我们的重要组成部分
testing stack uh they're called dev nets so you might have interacted with test nets in the past
测试堆栈UH它们称为开发网络，因此您过去可能已经与测试网进行了互动
the major difference is that dev nets are really short-lived about maybe even a few months and then
主要区别在于，开发网确实大约几个月的时间很短，然后
they're down there's absolutely no um long-term support for dev nets and they might even be local
他们掉下来绝对没有对开发网的长期支持，甚至可能是本地人
they might just last like half an hour test nets on the other hand are more public we have a reliable
另一方面，他们可能只能持续半小时的测试网，我们有一个可靠的
testnet schedule right now so you can expect testnets like go girly uh sorry not girly but
现在的测试网络时间表，因此您可以期待像Go Girly这样的测试网，对不起，不是Girly，但是
holsky and sepolia to last for a certain number of years you can expect the network to be up
Holsky和Sepolia持续一年
so the devnets themselves are um testing mirror of the ethereum base layer so they have the same
因此，devnet本身是以太坊基层的um测试镜，所以它们具有相同的
components that ethereum main net has uh they contain execution clients they contain consensus
以太坊主要网拥有UH的组件，它们包含执行客户端，它们包含共识
layer, beacon node clients, it can contain validators, you have MEV infrastructure on there.
层，信标节点客户端，它可以包含验证器，您的MEV基础架构在那里。
And the way we do it is because we control the entire devnet ecosystem, we can set it up in
我们这样做的方式是因为我们控制了整个DEVNET生态系统，我们可以将其设置在
whatever configuration that we want. So you could imagine that for whatever reason, we want to test
无论我们想要什么配置。因此，您可以想象，无论出于何种原因，我们都想测试
a super majority bug, right? So we can set up that a majority of client validators are running a
超级错误，对吗？因此，我们可以设置大多数客户端验证者正在运行
specific client and we can simulate that incident. So having this level of control on devnets allows
特定的客户，我们可以模拟该事件。因此，在DEVNETS上拥有这种控制水平可以
us to deploy forks and changes without affecting mainnet, without affecting any stable testing
我们在不影响主网的情况下部署叉子和更改，而不会影响任何稳定的测试
network or anything. While they are still public, so community members, so you guys, for example,
网络或任何东西。他们仍然是公开的，所以社区成员，所以你们，例如
are more than welcome to come test with us. An example, right now we don't have any
非常欢迎与我们一起测试。一个例子，现在我们没有任何
uh petra devnet up we're planning on having one up over the next few weeks but uh we do have
UH PETRA DEVNET UP我们打算在接下来的几周内实现一个
vocal devnets up for example so you could uh take part in a vocal devnet try and break it and if you
例如，人声devnets例如，您可以参加人声devnet尝试打破它，如果您
break it then it's going to make its way into a fix and you have your fame there um yeah and like
打破它，然后它将进入修复程序，您在那里成名，嗯，喜欢
i mentioned before you're able to design all of these edge cases these network faults and things
我在您可以设计所有这些网络故障和事物之前提到
like that that are kind of harder to do anywhere else and testing today so uh we actively are
像这样的其他地方和今天的测试更难以做，所以我们积极地是
talking about a petra devnet um tbd maybe in the next week two weeks you will be seeing something
谈论佩特拉·德维尼特（Petra Devnet）um tbd，也许在接下来的两个星期里，你会看到一些东西
uh a lot of our focus right now is on work so trying to get some work transition tests going
呃，我们现在的很多重点都在工作，所以试图进行一些工作过渡测试
making sure the tooling is ready for the next fork because we have some amount of downtime to work on
确保该工具已准备好用于下一个叉子，因为我们有一些停机时间进行工作
it right now. We recently relaunched the Costinan devnet with some changes that were found from
现在。最近，我们重新启动了Costinan Devnet，并从中发现了一些更改
earlier iterations. We're also doing some prototyping. So inclusion lists is one strong
较早的迭代。我们也在做一些原型。因此，包容列表是一个强大的
example. Another one is EIP-7441, which is WISC, where you have some amount of base layer
例子。另一个是EIP-7441，即WISC，您有一定数量的基层层
validator privacy. So we also have some long-running testnets that achieve that.
验证器隐私。因此，我们也有一些长期运行的测试网。
it's also not just, sorry dev nets that achieve that, it's not just future folks that dev nets can use.
不仅是，对不起的开发网络可以实现这一目标，不仅仅是开发网络可以使用的未来人。
Sometimes current clients also need some sort of testing, right?
有时目前的客户也需要某种测试，对吗？
For example, it's EthereumJS wanting to have snapsync support on their client.
例如，是希望在其客户那里获得Snapsync支持的以太列赛。
And doing this on a full-fledged test net is quite heavy.
在全面的测试网上这样做很重。
You have a lot of blocks, it's a lot of state.
您有很多障碍，这是很多状态。
you might not want to target that immediately.
您可能不想立即定位这一点。
So we set up a small-scale Ethereum.js snapsink test
因此，我们设置了一个小规模的以太坊。JSSnapsink测试
that they can just use for that use case.
他们只能将其用于该用例。
And we often do run, we call them big boy beacon chain tests.
而且我们经常运行，我们称它们为大男孩信标连锁测试。
So they are maxing out any one parameter of the beacon chain
因此，他们最大化了信标链的任何一个参数
that we think makes sense to max out.
我们认为最大化是有意义的。
So an example might be increasing the validators
因此一个例子可能正在增加验证者
to a million and a half validators or two million validators.
到一百万半验证者或200万验证器。
And this is indeed a test that we ran before committing to how big the validator set on Holsky will be,
这确实是我们在承诺霍尔斯基（Holsky）上的验证器的大小之前进行的测试，
so that we know that the clients are actually able to handle such a big network.
这样我们就知道客户实际上能够处理如此大的网络。
Same with blobs. We would spam blobs and see, hey, if in our controlled environment,
与斑点一样。我们会垃圾邮件斑点，嘿，如果在我们的受控环境中，
we're not able to do X amount of blobs, there's no way that we'd be able to do this on mainnet.
我们无法进行X斑点，我们无法在主网上执行此操作。
So this sort of devnet level testing allows us to achieve a lot of different things there.
因此，这种DEVNET级测试使我们能够在那里实现许多不同的事情。
But dev nets require a lot of coordination.
但是开发网络需要很多协调。
You would want a bunch of client teams.
您需要一群客户团队。
You would probably expect a DevOps team to be setting up this network.
您可能会期望DevOps团队建立此网络。
And it takes some amount of effort to coordinate everyone.
而且需要一定的努力来协调每个人。
And we don't want to always do that, especially if we put in all of that effort
而且我们不想总是这样做，尤其是如果我们付出了所有这些努力
and the network breaks just because a client didn't start up
网络仅仅是因为客户没有启动而破裂
or just because someone had the wrong specification implemented it's a lot of toil for
或仅仅因为有人实施了错误的规范，这很辛苦
too little effort and at some point last year we realized this and we wanted to push for we want
努力太少了，去年的某个时候，我们意识到这一点，我们想推动我们想要的
to do a heavy push for local testing because then i can spin up a really small network
要大力推动本地测试，因为我可以旋转一个非常小的网络
to sanity check that everything is working before i commit to the bigger devnet
理智，请检查一切在我致力于更大的DEVNET之前是否有效
so this also allows us for faster iterations so i can have i don't know 10 different parameter
因此，这也使我们进行更快的迭代，因此我可以不知道10个不同的参数
change is running over 20 different dev nets all running on one laptop um and then figure out yeah
更改超过20个不同的开发网，全部运行在一台笔记本电脑上，然后找出是的
okay i found this bug in this one this one and that one and let's see which is the um optimum
好吧，我在这个和那个的一个中发现了这个错误，让我们看看哪个是最佳的
that i i'll commit to for a dev it also allows us to work async on a lot of features so if client a
我将承诺为开发人员承诺它也使我们能够在许多功能上进行异步，因此如果客户端
and b say they are feature complete we normally publish like a config that everyone can use and
b说它们是功能完整的，我们通常会像每个人都可以使用的配置一样发布，并且
and then you can update and append your own client and see if interop works.
然后，您可以更新和附加自己的客户端，看看Interop是否有效。
And if it works, then you already know that when the devnet happens, the devnet will also work.
而且，如果有效，那么您已经知道，当DevNet发生时，DEVNET也将起作用。
And to also help this local fast iterative testing, we also allow you to configure slot
为了帮助此局部快速迭代测试，我们还允许您配置插槽
times, you can change the fork epoch version, you can do the entire map workflow. So there's a lot
时间，您可以更改叉子时期版本，可以完成整个地图工作流程。所以有很多
of really nice things that can happen here and i'm going to go through a couple of examples of
在这里可能会发生的非常好的事情，我将介绍几个例子
how these local testings look and i do definitely want to focus on this for a bit especially in the
这些本地测试的外观，我肯定想关注这一点，尤其是在
context of prototyping because i think it is a really really powerful tool for not only
原型的背景是因为我认为它不仅是一个非常强大的工具
understanding how ethereum works but to know what components ethereum has and for whenever you feel
了解以太坊的工作原理，但要知道以太坊拥有的组件以及每当您感觉到
ready how to test your own changes on uh sort of your own network that you get some more
准备如何在您自己的网络上测试自己的更改，以便您获得更多
confidence of it um and this setup that we have um it's also very scalable and we've kind of
它的信心，我们拥有的设置也非常可扩展，我们有
achieved this via this tool that's called kurtosis so kurtosis is um you can imagine it as a cli tool
通过此工具（称为峰度）实现了这一点
it consumes um yaml and then it passes this yaml via the definitions and the definitions are all
它消耗um yaml，然后通过定义通过此yaml，定义都是
in starlark which is a python-based language and what it spits out is something that docker as well
在Starlark中，这是一种基于Python的语言，它吐出的内容也是Docker
as the kubernetes engine can understand so you're going from a yaml definition into a ethereum
正如Kubernetes引擎可以理解的那样，您将从YAML的定义转变为以太坊
network that is deployed either on your local docker machine or on a remote kubernetes instance
部署在您本地Docker机器或远程Kubernetes实例上的网络
The reason we want to support both of these is for local docker instance it's great if you just want two, three nodes, you just want to set up something quick, you want to see if a fork works in under five minutes, and then you're done.
我们要支持这两个的原因是对于本地码头实例，如果您只想要两个，三个节点，您只想快速设置一些东西，您想看看叉子是否在五分钟内工作，然后您才能使用'完成。
Whereas if we want to do bigger tests, say you want 500 nodes because you want to test some edge case, or you want to make use of the Kubernetes layer abstractions that are offered to you, for example, chaos testing.
尽管我们想进行更大的测试，但要说您想要500个节点，因为您想测试某些边缘情况，或者想使用提供给您的Kubernetes层抽象，例如，混乱测试。
testing, right? Then you want to support the Kubernetes engine as well. So we kind of offer,
测试，对吗？然后，您也需要支持Kubernetes引擎。所以我们提供了
or you want to have a more production system where it can run in the cloud, someone can access data
或者您想拥有一个可以在云中运行的更多生产系统，有人可以访问数据
from it, you can have like a public dev net in the cloud, you can use that Kubernetes engine for it.
从中，您可以像云中的公共开发网络一样，可以使用Kubernetes引擎。
It's all configurable, you can have a look at the kurtosis documentation. And there is a repository,
都是可以配置的，您可以查看峰度文档。还有一个存储库，
I highly, highly recommend that you guys are also going to this repository. And please over the
我强烈建议你们也去这个存储库。请在
course of this call try and download kurtosis as well as make sure that docker is on your local
此通话过程尝试下载峰度，并确保Docker在您的本地
machine because towards the end if you want uh and try to run some of these examples and you
机器是因为到最后，如果您想要UH并尝试运行其中一些示例，您
have questions we can also talk about the questions it's extremely simple to run and i'm
有问题我们也可以谈论非常简单的问题，我我
just going to go through this definition once because we're going to be using this definition
只是要仔细研究这个定义，因为我们将使用此定义
also later on so kurtosis name of the cli you're using you want to run something an enclave is sort
稍后，您也在使用CLI的名称上，您想运行飞地是分类的
of namespace it contains what this network will be called and other networks won't touch this
命名空间中包含该网络将被调用的内容，而其他网络不会触摸此网络
so it's just some amount of separation you can have more than one enclave on your machine you
因此，这只是一定程度的分离，您可以在机器上有一个以上的飞地
can do a lot of fun things with names with enclaves we normally just call it ethereum
可以用飞地做很多有趣的事情，我们通常称其为以太坊
network or each two or whatever you want to call it the next github link that is pasted there
网络或每个两个或您想称其为粘贴的下一个github链接
is the starlark definition of what the network needs to look like this is just generic understanding
是网络需要看起来的星球定义只是通用的理解
This definition, for example, defines what a get node is.
例如，该定义定义了一个get节点是什么。
It defines what the YAML fields mean.
它定义了YAML字段的含义。
What do I do with Genesis time?
我该如何处理创世纪时间？
It defines all of those things.
它定义了所有这些东西。
It's very extendable.
这是非常可扩展的。
And the really cool part is if you clone this Git repository
真正很酷的部分是如果您克隆此git存储库
and you make a change to the star lock, you don't even need to push it.
而且您要更改星星锁，甚至不需要推动它。
You can just replace that remote GitHub URL with dot
您只需用dot替换该远程github URL
or whatever the path, the local path of the repository.
或任何路径，存储库的本地路径。
and kurtosis will pick it up and kurtosis won't then deploy a network as defined in github it'll
峰度会捡起它，而峰度不会在github中部署网络，它将
deploy the network as defined in your local machine so not only can you modify parameters
部署本地计算机中定义的网络，因此您不仅可以修改参数
of a network you can also modify what it means to be a network in itself um the next one is args
在网络中，您还可以修改成为网络本身的含义，而下一个是ARGS
file and then you pass a file which has a bunch of predefined parameters and i'm going to go through
文件，然后您传递一个具有一堆预定义参数的文件，我将通过
a couple of them to show you what type of networks you can set up with this local testing tool.
其中一些可以通过此本地测试工具向您展示可以设置哪种类型的网络。
So here's an example of a YAML definition. So you define the participants. You're saying you want
因此，这是YAML定义的示例。因此，您定义参与者。你是说你想要
one participant that is a get Tecku node. So this will be get EL, Tecku, CL, as well as
一个是get tecku节点的参与者。因此，这将是EL，Tecku，Cl以及
validator and then you want one participant that is a nether mind EL and
验证者，然后您希望一个参与者是一个幽默的思想EL和
prism CL as well as validator you can also override every single part of this
棱镜CL和验证器您还可以覆盖此的每个部分
by the way and I will talk about overrides later on but every single bit
顺便说一句，我将在以后再说一遍，但每一点
of kurtosis is overridable here and then you can you you are defining here
峰度的毛发病在这里不足，然后您可以在这里定义
that you want some additional services you want this network to have a
您想要一些其他服务，希望该网络有一个
transaction spammer so that there's some transaction load on the network you want
交易垃圾邮件发送者，以便您想要的网络上有一些交易负载
this network to have a blob spammer some transaction some blob load on this network
这个网络要有斑点垃圾邮件发送者某些交易在此网络上负载一些斑点负载
dora is an explorer so it will give you a url you can access a local explorer that will help
Dora是探险家，因此它将为您提供一个URL，您可以访问本地资源管理器
you understand what's going on in your network you'll be collecting all the metrics and pushing
您了解网络中正在发生的事情，您将收集所有指标并推动
it to your own prometheus instance and a snooper sits between all the apis that are available so
它是您自己的普罗米修斯实例，一个侦探者位于所有可用的API之间
between your engine in your engine api in your beacon api and every one of them and it just spits
在信标API中的发动机API中与每一个发动机API之间的引擎之间，它只是吐口水
out every single thing that's happening on that interface so it's a man in the middle
消除该界面上正在发生的每件事，所以它是一个中间的男人
um and it's very very useful for if you're doing a new fork and you actually want to know hey the
嗯，如果您正在做新叉，并且实际上想知道嘿，这非常有用
cl sent something and that broke the el can i maybe figure out what message the el sent me so i can
Cl发送了一些东西，这打破了EL，我可以弄清楚EL向我发送了什么消息，以便我可以
reproduce this bug uh saves us a bunch of time having this sort of man in the middle and key
重现此错误UH为我们节省了很多时间，使这种人在中间和钥匙
manager enabled enables the key manager API and you can do whatever you want with the key manager
启用管理器启用密钥管理器API，您可以使用密钥管理器进行任何操作
API as well. And I'm guessing a lot of you are in the MEV environment or at least curious about
API也是。我猜你们中的很多人都在MEV环境中，或者至少对
the MEV environment. And we also support the entire MEV workflow on Kurtosis. So if you do,
MEV环境。我们还支持整个MEV工作流程有关峰度的工作流程。所以，如果这样做，
for example, mev type full, then it will spin up a local relay, it will spin up a local
例如，MEV类型已满，然后它将旋转本地继电器，它将旋转本地接力赛
database for accessing all the relay validator registrations, it will spin up mev boost so that
用于访问所有继电器验证器注册的数据库，它将旋转MEV提升，以便
your validator can connect to the relay, it will spin up a builder, it will use all open source
您的验证器可以连接到继电器，它将旋转一个构建器，它将使用所有开源
images, so most of them are from FlashPots and you can override any of them in case you're building
图像，所以大多数来自闪存锅，您可以覆盖其中的任何一个，以防您建造
your own relay in case you're building your own map boost implementation or whatever it is and
如果您建立自己的地图提升实施或任何内容，那么您自己的继电器以及
one important thing to note here if you notice in the previous list there was a participants
如果您在上一个列表中注意到参与者，请注意的一件重要的事情要注意
whereas here there's no participants so whenever you don't specify something in kurtosis it just
而在这里没有参与者，所以每当您不指定某些内容时，
uses the default and the default is i think one participant with the geth in lighthouse so that's
使用默认值，默认值是我认为一个参与者在灯塔中与Geth一起
what will be spun up in this network um and here we're also having a few additional services so
在这个网络中会吐出的内容，在这里我们还提供了一些其他服务，所以
So this custom flood that comes up and what custom flood does is it sends very malleable transactions so that there's some juicy payloads that the builder can build.
因此，这种自定义洪水以及自定义洪水的作用是发送非常可延展的交易，因此建造者可以建造一些多汁的有效载荷。
Otherwise, the builder is not building anything that the validator is going to propose with.
否则，构建器不会构建验证者将要提出的任何东西。
And what I meant by overrideable, if you look at the MEV params, so I'm launching with custom flood.
如果您查看MEV参数，那么我的意思是我的意思，所以我正在使用自定义洪水进行启动。
that's also available earlier and I'm specifying the MEV relay image and what this means is you
这也很早就可以了，我正在指定MEV继电器图像，这意味着您
no longer want the default MEV relay image that Kurtosis ships with but instead you have your
不再想要Kurtosis携带的默认MEV继电器图像，而是您拥有
own MEV boost relay that you've implemented and you want to use your docker image there
拥有您已经实施的MEV Boost继电器，您想在那里使用Docker Image
so that's also possible and this is extremely useful for us in rapid fork testing so we can
因此，这也是可能的，这对我们进行快速分叉测试非常有用，因此我们可以
have the latest version that has not been released yet override it here and
具有尚未发布的最新版本在此处覆盖它
it's only if it breaks something it will only break something my local testing
只有当它打破某些东西时，它只会破坏我的本地测试
environment nowhere else and to make things faster you can also override
环境无处
certain parameters so anything that makes sense to override in the in the
某些参数，因此任何有意义的覆盖的参数
consensus specs there's a file called conflict or gamma so this is the
共识规格有一个称为冲突或伽玛的文件，所以这是
definition of what a beacon chain looks like anything there that makes sense to
信标链的定义看起来像是有意义的
override we allow you to override here so one of them is seconds per slot so ethereum beacon chain
覆盖我们允许您在这里覆盖，因此其中一个是每个插槽的秒
today has 12 seconds per slot and here i'm saying that's too long i don't actually care about
今天每个插槽有12秒，我在这里说这太长了，我实际上并不在乎
waiting for 12 seconds i don't actually care about finality i just want to make sure that my payload
等待12秒我实际上并不关心最终性，我只想确保我的有效载荷
is getting delivered so you're overriding it to once every three seconds and now you have four
即将交付，所以您将其覆盖每三秒钟一次，现在您有四个
times the number of calls uh happening which means the chances of whatever you're testing to be
次通话的数量嗯，这意味着您要测试的任何机会
triggered or probably four times as likely. So, yeah, so the next thing is, I've shown you guys
触发或大概是四倍。所以，是的，接下来的事情是，我告诉你们
how you do some local testing. The question is now how do I actually prototype things, right?
您如何进行一些本地测试。问题现在是我如何实际原型的事情，对吗？
So like I've mentioned earlier, Kurtosis works on the concept of everything can be overwritten
因此，就像我之前提到的那样，Kurtosis在所有事物的概念上都可以覆盖
outside of the network basics.
在网络基础之外。
So a simple example is in the mainnet spec,
因此，一个简单的示例是Mainnet规范，
there will always be 32 slots per e-box.
每个e-box总会有32个插槽。
You can try to override it.
您可以尝试覆盖它。
It's not supported by any client.
任何客户都不支持它。
So you can specify it in kurtosis if you want.
因此，如果需要，您可以在峰度中指定它。
We're just going to ignore it
我们只是要忽略它
because it's a sane check
因为这是一个理智的检查
that we know will break the network.
我们知道会破坏网络。
Like that, we have a lot of sanity checks
这样，我们有很多理智检查
that make sure you can't break your setup too much.
这确保您不能过多打破设置。
So as long as you read the docs,
因此，只要您阅读文档，
as long as you change something that we specify in the docs,
只要您更改我们在文档中指定的内容，
chances are it will work quite well.
有可能运作良好。
In case you want to test protocol changes,
如果您要测试协议更改，
you might want to update or override the client images itself.
您可能需要更新或覆盖客户端图像本身。
So you don't want to use NetherMind latest.
因此，您不想最新使用Nethermind。
You might want to use NetherMind fork that you have built yourself
您可能想使用自己已经建立的nethermind叉
in order to test new tools.
为了测试新工具。
You can run an existing kurtosis network.
您可以运行现有的峰度网络。
You can run like a tiny kurtosis network.
您可以像微小的峰度网络一样运行。
And once at the end of the kurtosis run,
在峰度结束时，
it will give you all the API endpoints.
它将为您提供所有API端点。
And your tool can connect to those APIs
您的工具可以连接到这些API
and you can test building whatever you want to build.
您可以测试构建您想构建的任何东西。
An example is we've built a local explorer with this.
一个例子是，我们为此构建了一个本地资源管理器。
So we no longer have to sync a whole network.
因此，我们不再需要同步整个网络。
You don't have to do all of that.
您不必做所有这些。
You can just sync a local network, which is a lot faster.
您可以同步本地网络，这要快得多。
and then you can make sure that your explorer works as expected before you do anything wild
然后，您可以确保您的探险家在做任何疯狂之前就可以按预期工作
a lot of people also do this for smaller tools that they're building so there's this one tool
许多人也为他们构建的较小工具做到了这一点，所以有一个工具
where you can have a CLI that kind of notifies you when your validator is selected for proposals
当您选择验证器以进行建议时，您可以在哪里可以通知您的CLI
it's being built by someone who works at T-Mobile as far as I'm sorry Telecom as far as I know
据我所知，我是由在T-Mobile工作的人建造的
and he's using kurtosis to run it locally so connect to a local devnet so he doesn't he
而且他正在使用峰度在本地运行它，所以请连接到当地的Devnet，所以他不是
controls the entire validator set and he wants his tool to do a lot of other things and he has
控制整个验证器集，他希望他的工具做很多其他事情，他有
entire control without relying on a public network without spending gigabytes to download something
整个控制而无需依靠公共网络而无需花费千兆字节下载某些内容
keep it in sync etc and in case you want to test quicker forks like i showed earlier you can change
将其保持在同步等，如果您想像我之前显示的那样要快速测试较快的叉子，您可以更改
the second per slot you can change when the fork happens so you can say hey why don't i have my
叉子发生时，您可以更改的每个插槽第二个插槽，所以您可以说嘿，为什么我没有我的
fork happen at epoch one already so if i do epoch one as well as set the seconds per slot to three
叉子已经发生在epoch的一个
seconds then pretty much in about two minutes you're testing a fork which is extremely fast
几秒钟，然后在大约两分钟内您要测试一个非常快的叉子
when you want to iterate stuff when you want to prototype type things and here's an example
当您想在想原型打字时迭代内容时，这是一个示例
of prototype testing so vocal is a huge beast and it's a big fork and we've been trying to
在原型测试中，人声是一只巨大的野兽，这是一个大叉子，我们一直在努力
support it with local testing as much as we can so here's an example of how um we can test the
尽可能多地通过本地测试来支持它
transition as a worker transition locally so if you copy this and you run it in kurtosis you
作为工人在本地过渡的过渡，如果您复制此并在Kurtosis中运行它，
you're basically testing a worker transition so i'm going to go through this from top to bottom
您基本上是在测试工人的过渡
so what happens is right now i'm specifying a participant list and i'm saying i want a geth
因此，发生的事情是现在我要指定参与者列表，我说我想要一个Geth
node and i want the geth node to run this particular docker image this particular docker
节点和我希望Geth节点运行此特定的Docker图像此特定的Docker
image is built from a fork of geth by guillaume who's working on worker and the for uh the yeah
图像是由正在从事工人工作的Guillaume的Geth的叉子建造的，是的
he's doing a transition post a network genesis and there's a lodestar image that g11 tech has
他正在做一个网络创世纪的过渡，并且有G11 Tech拥有的Lodestar图像
built that supports the worker transition because both the el as well as the cl need to have a
支持工人过渡的建造，因为EL和CL都需要一个
concept of what the fork is for it's just to work and I want three of them
叉子的概念只是为了工作，我想要三个
and you can specify count as whatever you want and it will replicate the same
您可以将计数指定为您想要的任何东西，并且它将复制相同
definition for all the participants and then in my network parameters I'm
所有参与者的定义，然后在我的网络参数中
specifying that at the time it was called an Electra fork epoch will still
指定当时被称为electra叉时期
be basing so don't pay attention to that particular name but it is Electra fork
基于基础，所以不要关注那个特定的名字，但它是伊莱克
epoch1 so the transition will happen at epoch1 the network will start roughly 100 seconds after
epoch1因此，过渡将在epoch1上发生，网络将在大约100秒开始
i run my kurtosis command and you might want to do this for a certain number of reasons maybe
我运行我的Kurtosis命令，您可能想这样做，原因有很多原因
there's an amount of time that takes for um for you to spin up all your uh terminal windows with
UM需要花费大量时间来旋转所有UH终端窗口
the logs maybe you want to wait some time for some processing that your node has to do it in it
日志也许您想等待一些时间来处理您的节点必须在其中进行的处理
Maybe you just don't want to have it immediately so you don't miss anything.
也许您只是不想立即拥有它，所以您不会错过任何东西。
So, in this case, we're just doing it with Genesis Delay of 100 seconds.
因此，在这种情况下，我们只是以100秒的创世纪延迟来进行。
And then Snoopers enables, so I'll be able to see each and every single call that happens
然后窥探者可以启用，所以我可以看到发生的每个呼叫
between the EL and CL, and this was very useful early on because the CL dev could say, oh,
在EL和CL之间，这很早就很有用，因为CL Dev可以说，哦，
this is how I interpreted the spec.
这就是我解释规格的方式。
I wanted to have these calls, and the EL dev is like, yeah, but that puts me in this state.
我想打来这些电话，而El Dev就像是的，但这使我处于这种状态。
Maybe you send it this way instead.
也许您以这种方式发送。
it helps us to actually see what's going on.
它可以帮助我们实际查看发生了什么。
Persistence true is important in case you want to have this network running for a longer amount of time.
如果您想让该网络运行更长的时间，则持久性很重要。
It just means if a container restarts or whatever, it starts back up with the same state.
这只是意味着如果容器重新启动或其他任何内容，则以同一状态开始备份。
So if you have persistent true, you could say kudos to stop participant number two.
因此，如果您坚持不懈，您可以说敬意，以阻止参与者第二。
You can wait 10 seconds or whatever, two minutes until some blocks are built,
您可以等待10秒或其他时间，两分钟，直到建造一些块，
and then you can start that particular instance again,
然后您可以再次启动该特定实例，
and then that instance will start syncing to the head of the chain.
然后该实例将开始同步到链的头部。
So you're also testing sync in a way.
因此，您还可以在某种程度上测试同步。
So you can use this for a lot of really cool things.
因此，您可以将其用于很多非常酷的东西。
Or it could also be something as simple as,
否则也可能很简单，
hey, if I built a client and I shut down the node and I started back up,
嘿，如果我建立了一个客户端，然后关闭节点，然后开始备份，
will it even start back up?
它甚至会重新开始吗？
That is also something you want to test, right?
这也是您要测试的东西，对吗？
And yeah, I'm wanting to launch some additional services.
是的，我想推出一些其他服务。
services one of them is dora the explorer and the other one is the certer i won't talk about
服务之一是探险家多拉（Dora），另一个是我不会谈论的Certer
a certain now um i don't want to overload you guys with tools but yeah for now kind of get this is
现在某个嗯，我不想让你们用工具超载，但是现在有点是
how you would do prototype testing so if you have your own el your own cl fork and you want to test
您将如何进行原型测试，因此，如果您有自己的EL叉叉，并且想测试
it all you have to do is replace el image and cl image and maybe a good first example is fork any
您要做的就是替换El Image和Cl图像，也许是一个很好的第一个示例是分叉
one client it doesn't matter which one whatever language you're comfortable in and just add some
一个客户都没关系到哪一种您喜欢的语言，只需添加一些语言
log message saying you were here build a docker image put the docker image here and then once you
日志消息说您在这里构建一个Docker映像，然后将Docker图像放在此处
start the network in the log it will say you were here it's a nice first start to understand how the
在日志中启动网络，它将说您在这里，这是一个很好的开始，以了解如何了解
prototype testing system will work so once people are kind of comfortable with local testing what we
原型测试系统将起作用，因此一旦人们对本地测试感到满意
normally do is upgrade to remote testing. And I've mentioned the reasons earlier, remote testing
通常，DO会升级到远程测试。我已经提到了较早的原因，远程测试
needs a lot more synchronous time. We try to do it only once we feel like clients are ready.
需要更多的同步时间。我们只有一旦我们觉得客户就准备就绪，我们就尝试这样做。
Worker, for example, has a lot of local testing for a rebase that's going on, but we've deployed
例如，工人对正在进行的重生进行了许多本地测试，但是我们已经部署了
some older versions for public devnet testing. Even though they do take some amount of effort
一些用于公共DEVNET测试的较旧版本。即使他们确实付出了一些努力
in time, we want to make them as easy as possible to set up when we're doing it. And
随着时间的流逝，我们希望使它们尽可能容易地进行设置。和
they used to be very error prone and time consuming, because the definition of how to
他们曾经很容易出错且耗时，因为如何定义如何
spin up a dev net, what parameters are there it. I think two, three years ago, every single team
旋转开发网络，其中有什么参数。我认为三年前，每个团队
was maintaining their own start test net scripts earlier, at least that's largely how that worked.
在早些时候维护自己的开始测试网脚本，至少这在很大程度上是如何工作的。
and I'm sure they still do, and it's very good that they do.
而且我确定他们仍然会这样做，而且他们做得很好。
But it gets hard to do interrupt testing
但是很难进行中断测试
if you're reliant on those scripts.
如果您依靠这些脚本。
It's harder to modify things.
修改事物很难。
And it becomes very easy for a drift to occur
而且漂移很容易发生
between setup configs and customizations you might need.
在您可能需要的设置配置和自定义之间。
So, Verkle needs quite a few customizations
因此，Verkle需要很多自定义
on quite a few levels.
在相当多的层面上。
So, we have...
所以，我们有...
Verkle has a specific type of genesis,
Verkle具有特定类型的创世纪，
and that genesis requires you to use a fork of another library that is using a fork of another
而且该创世纪要求您使用另一个正在使用另一个叉子的叉子的叉子
library so there's like three levels of forks that are required and needed to be maintained for it
图书馆，大约需要三个级别的叉子，需要维护并需要维护
and now you can imagine if we're doing this across many clients it just starts to get very tedious it
现在您可以想象，如果我们在许多客户中这样做，它就开始变得非常乏味
there's a huge drift i might not want to
有一个我可能不想的巨大漂移
you'll drift so much that you might not be able to merge stuff back into your main whenever you're
您会漂移太多，以至于您可能无法在您的主要身上合并回主
So what we did was we split the bare-bones logic of
所以我们所做的就是我们分开了裸词的逻辑
What is a node and?
什么是节点？
What needs to happen on a network ie generate validator keys get Genesis?
网络上需要发生什么IE生成验证器密钥获得创世纪？
Start a node
启动一个节点
Wait for a node to start up get the nodes peer-to-peer address
等待节点启动获取节点点对点地址
Shut down a node clean up node
关闭节点清理节点
we've taken these generic definitions and we've used a we normally write all
我们采用了这些通用定义，并且使用了通常写全部的我们
of these things in ansible ansible is a I'm going to call it a fancy scripting
在Ansible Ansible中，这些事情是我称之为花哨的脚本
language it's not a language it's like a fancy scripting methodology to do things
语言不是一种语言，就像一种花哨的脚本方法
across a lot of nodes a lot of cloud instances and there's a concept of a
在许多节点中，很多云实例，并且有一个概念
role so a role is sort of like a function that you can call pass some parameters and what you passed
角色因此，角色就像一个函数，您可以调用传递一些参数以及您传递的内容
in is what happens so we've generalized these concepts into this ansible collection general
在发生的是，我们已经将这些概念概括为这个Ansible Collection一般
and then we've moved generic components into their own tools so genesis is a concept that
然后，我们将通用组件转移到了他们自己的工具中，因此创世纪是一个概念，
almost every single devnet has to do at some point right if you don't have genesis you don't
如果您没有创世纪，几乎每个Devnet都必须在某个时候做
of the genesis files the network will not be able to start up so we built this genesis generator
网络将无法启动的Genesis文件，因此我们构建了Genesis Generator
uh tool all it is is a docker file that wraps through a lot of tools and scripts so there's some
uh工具，它只是一个docker文件，它包含许多工具和脚本，因此有一些
sanity checks some logic some methodology on how you call it but it's very configurable you're able
理智检查一些有关您如何称呼它的方法，但非常可配置
to handle the case of vocal that i just gave you where there's fork over fork canonicalized there
处理我刚刚给您的声音的情况
as well as mainnet ethereum as well as shadowfox as well as the next extra devnet all within this
以及主网以及ShadowFox以及下一个额外的Devnet以及其中的所有内容
one repository and the interface between this repository and the ansible connection is defined
一个存储库以及此存储库与Ansible连接之间的接口定义
so they're tightly coupled in that way um but you can modify both if you want um and you can get a
因此，它们以这种方式紧密结合，但是如果您想要UM，您可以同时修改，并且可以得到一个
new different thing and the next problem was tooling if for example i have work um the
新的不同事物，下一个问题是工具，例如我有工作
work devnet changes so many things that my explorer might not work out of the box
工作DEVNET改变了很多事情，我的探险家可能无法开箱即用
i might need forks of my explorer it gets hard to maintain that and it gets hard to keep them up
我可能需要我的探险家的叉子，很难维持这一点，而且很难保持它们
when a network is running it gets hard to scale them up it gets yeah you have operational issues
当网络运行时，很难将它们扩展到它，是的，您有操作问题
that so what we do is we use kubernetes and there's a concept called git ops so git ops is
我们要做的就是使用kubernetes，并且有一个名为git ops的概念，所以git ops是
basically what is on git is what gets deployed on your kubernetes instance it's one to one so you
基本上，git上的东西是在您的kubernetes实例上部署的是一对一，所以您
define what you want on github and uh kubernetes makes this git ops thing we use argo it makes it
定义您在Github和Uh Kubernetes上想要的东西使我们使用Argo的git操作事物
happen for you and these definitions happen via um another packaging language or packaging system
发生在您身上，这些定义通过UM另一个包装语言或包装系统发生
called Helm Charts. So this will, for example, spin up all of our tooling for us. So
称为Helm图表。因此，例如，这将为我们旋转我们的所有工具。所以
we now have a way to spin up Ethereum nodes, we have a way to spin up what a network is,
我们现在有一种方法可以旋转以太坊节点，我们有一种方法可以旋转网络是什么，
and we have a way to spin up what the tools are. The question is, how do you bring all of these
我们有一种方法可以旋转工具是什么。问题是，您如何带来所有这些
disparaging things together, right? So what we've done is we've generalized the setup
一起贬低事物，对吗？所以我们做的是我们已经概括了设置
for all testnets possible into this repository called template testnet so
对于所有可能进入该存储库的测试网称为模板testnet，
what template testnet does is it has
什么模板测试网是
template testnet has terraform code to spin up the network it then uses the
Template TestNet具有terraform代码来旋转网络，然后使用
ansible code as you define it to spin up the nodes as well as to spin up Genesis
当您定义它以旋转节点并旋转创世纪时，Ansible代码
information and get all of that and put it somewhere. And then it also spins up the
信息并获取所有这些并将其放在某个地方。然后它也旋转
entire definition for what your tooling needs to look like. And then once you push this entire
您的工具需要外观的整个定义。然后，一旦您推动了整个
thing to GitHub, GitOps just makes that tooling magically appear. So GitOps also makes sure that
github的事情是，Gitops只是使该工具神奇地出现。因此，Gitops还确保
your certificates appear, that your URLs look nice, that you have a load balancer in front,
您的证书出现了，您的URL看起来不错，您的URL在前面有负载平衡器，
all of those nice things are just taken care of so by splitting these things up into small
所有这些好东西都得到了照顾，因此将这些东西分成小
components and then combining them together in template testnet when i have a huge diff i can
组件，然后将它们混合在模板testnet中，当我有巨大的差异时，我可以
maintain it nicely in template testnet and move stuff back into the template as and when it
在模板测试网中很好地维护它，然后将其移回模板中
becomes important to move it back so you're very you're reducing the amount of drift that happens
向后移动它变得很重要，这样您就可以减少发生的漂移数量
between template uh that set up set up conflicts um we've successfully been using this for about
在设置建立冲突的模板UH之间，我们成功地将其用于大约
year now uh we did the entire denkoon fork at the same time testing whisk at the same time testing
一年，现在我们同时进行了整个Denkoon叉子的测试，同时进行测试
vocal at the same time doing other test nets and we've used this exact same infrastructure for our
发声同时进行其他测试网，我们为我们的
holesky nodes sepulia nodes all of them so i would say it's a relatively battle tested
holesky节点sepulia nodes ass last so
system and we're quite happy with it it's not to say it doesn't have its downsides but i would say
系统，我们对此非常满意，并不是说它没有弊端，但我会说
we've minimized the downsides as much as possible once someone understands the system
一旦某人理解系统，我们将弊端尽可能最小
um i'm not sure how we do questions but maybe this is a good spot to stop for questions um maybe
嗯，我不确定我们是怎么做问题的，但也许这是一个停止问题的好地方，也许嗯
mario or josh can tell me if that's a good idea yeah yeah great thank you so much kare uh we have
Mario或Josh可以告诉我，这是一个好主意，是的，很好，非常感谢您，我们有
uh discussion going on in this court here before asking questions and sometimes answering if you
UH讨论在这里在此法院进行，然后问问题，有时会回答您是否
if I'm able to answer.
如果我能回答。
So we've been going through it.
所以我们一直在经历。
People are running kurtosis here.
人们在这里运行峰度。
And let's see if you folks have any questions regarding
让我们看看你们是否对
the kurtosis.
峰度。
If you ran into some issues or something, let us know.
如果您遇到了一些问题或其他问题，请告诉我们。
I've also updated my local kurtosis binary
我还更新了当地的峰度二进制
and ran it again.
然后再次运行。
After a while, I have to say it works super nicely.
过了一会儿，我不得不说它效果很好。
The quick start is very easy compared
快速开始非常容易
to scrambling together bash script from some client team
拼凑出一些客户团队的bash脚本
to run a test net two, three years ago.
三年前运行两个测试网。
Like it's it's incredible.
就像它令人难以置信。
Yeah.
是的。
So yeah, there was a question.
是的，有一个问题。
How are the Docker images published?
Docker图像如何发布？
I shared them the itpandaops on Docker Hub.
我在Docker Hub上分享了他们的ItpandaOps。
Maybe if you can tell us more about that,
也许如果您可以告诉我们更多有关此的信息，
like how do you publish the images for testing it?
就像如何发布图像以进行测试？
Maybe whether you use also images from the client teams themselves?
也许您是否还使用客户团队本身的图像？
Yeah. Yeah.
是的。是的。
So we do it two ways. The first one is, maybe I can explain the problem to begin with. Before we started, every client team published Docker images, and they still do. But when or what triggers that Docker image publish varies wildly per client.
因此，我们采取了两种方式。第一个是，也许我可以解释要开始的问题。在开始之前，每个客户团队都发布了Docker图像，他们仍然可以。但是，何时或何时触发Docker Image发布的内容会差异很大。
So some client teams publish on latest, some client teams publish just the master main brand, some publish on each and every PR, some publish forks, some don't publish forks.
因此，某些客户团队在最新的客户团队上发布，一些客户团队仅发布主品牌，有些在每个PR上发布，有些发布叉子，有些不发布叉子。
It was a bit of a headache to always ping the dev working on the fork who then had to reach out to their DevOps person to build a Docker image for us.
始终在叉子上工作的开发人员始终与他们的Devops人联系以为我们建立码头图像，这真是令人头疼。
It gets very out of hand to do this.
这样做非常失控。
So what we did is, we, of course, when there's a client image, we use the client image, because I think that's a better way of testing.
因此，我们所做的是，当然，当有客户端映像时，我们会使用客户端图像，因为我认为这是一种更好的测试方式。
But when there isn't one for an early fork, for example, that is based off of a lot of other forks, we have a generalized Docker image builder.
但是，例如，如果没有其他叉子的早期叉子，这是基于许多其他叉子，我们就会有一个广义的Docker Image Builder。
I've shared the link in the private chat here, maybe Mario or Josh can move it over to the other chat.
我在这里的私人聊天中分享了链接，也许Mario或Josh可以将其转移到其他聊天中。
So this repository is able to build the client images of each and every single EL and CL out there.
因此，此存储库能够构建每个EL和CL的客户端图像。
There's a config.yaml file, and that config.yaml file is consumed by a scheduled builder.
有一个config.yaml文件，该config.yaml文件由计划的构建器消费。
So once every two hours, for a branch that we think is interesting to target, we build and preemptively publish images.
因此，每两个小时一次，对于我们认为可以针对的分支机构，我们会构建和先发制地发布图像。
So every image we publish will have a generalized name, so Latest Devil whatever, that gets updated
因此，我们发布的每个图像都会有一个广义的名称，因此最新的魔鬼都将更新
every two hours, as well as Latest Dash Char Commit Slug, so that when we do testing, I don't want to
每两个小时，以及最新的Dash Char提交slug，所以当我们进行测试时，我不想
run Latest and say, hey, my Latest is broken, because that means nothing to a developer. They
运行最新的话，说，嘿，我的最新消息被打破了，因为这对开发人员来说没什么意义。他们
want to know which commit you ran when you ran it. So you can choose in some cases for example CI
想知道您运行哪个提交您的跑步。因此，您可以在某些情况下选择例如CI
tests it makes sense to just use latest. In some cases when you're doing a local test it makes
测试只使用最新信息是有意义的。在某些情况下，当您进行本地测试时，
sense to specify exactly which commit hash you're doing. So you're able to build every single EL and
觉得确切地指定您正在做哪种提交哈希。因此，您可以构建每个EL和
CL and if you go to the actions tab over here we also support manually building them. You would
CL，如果您转到此处的“动作”标签，我们还支持手动构建它们。你会的
need to be invited to this repository to build because it gets very easy to spam the builder
需要邀请该存储库来构建，因为它很容易垃圾邮件
with requests otherwise but almost any client dev who wants access gets access there's no real
否则请求，但几乎所有想要访问访问权限的客户端都没有真实的客户
gating over there and it also if any of you really feels like you are actively testing something and
在那边的门控，如果你们中的任何一个人真的觉得自己正在积极测试某些东西，也是如此
you want access to this builder please let us know um and then if you choose for example you want to
您想访问此建筑商，请让我们知道UM，然后如果您选择了
build the Ethereum.js Docker image. And on the top right, there's a, there would be a run workflow.
构建以太坊。在右上角，有一个运行工作流程。
And with that, I can specify which repository to target and which branch and what the result in
因此，我可以指定要定位哪个存储库以及哪个分支以及哪些结果
Docker image should be called. And with that, I can do this ad hoc testing of, hey, I don't want
应该调用Docker图像。这样，我可以对此进行此临时测试，嘿，我不想
to push this fix into the Ethereum.js main repository. I have this tiny fork of mine that
将此修复程序推入以太坊。JS主存储库。我有一个我的小叉
no one else knows about, can you use this?
没有人知道，您可以使用这个吗？
I can still build a Docker image from there
我仍然可以从那里构建一个码头图像
without relying on my local machine.
不依靠我的本地机器。
And it will build ARM images, it will build
它将建立手臂图像，它将建立
Linux x86 images,
Linux X86图像，
it will build you a macOS image,
它将为您构建MacOS图像，
all the nice stuff.
所有的好东西。
And then everyone's just happy.
然后每个人都很高兴。
You can just target, it always
您可以定位，它总是
results in an ethpandaops
导致EthpandaOps
client name Docker image.
客户名称Docker映像。
Yeah. I hope that
是的。我希望那样
answered the question about the Docker image
回答了有关码头图像的问题
that's usually where we that's usually how we consume them yeah yeah it totally did uh i'm just
通常，我们通常是我们消耗它们的方式，是的，是的，完全做了
sharing my screen showing the actual uh if uh it gets lost in the uh presentation just wanted
分享我的屏幕显示实际的u，如果uh丢失了UH演示文稿，只是想要
to show that uh awesome yeah thank you so much barry um thank you so much for doing that and
为了证明真棒的是的，非常感谢Barry UM非常感谢您这样做，并且
if there are any issues questions or kurtosis you can still keep asking yes uh maybe we can
如果有任何问题或峰度，您仍然可以继续询问是的，也许我们可以
ask one more questions before we move forward um
在我们前进之前，请再问一个问题
um can i point kurtosis to the local get or is it only forks of remote repos or dicker images
嗯，我可以指向当地的峰度，还是只有远程存储库或dicker图像的分叉
so you can also point kurtosis to local anything so if you don't want to use if you use github
因此，您还可以将峰度指向本地任何事物，因此，如果您不想使用GitHub，
slash whatever then it's remote if you just point it to dot slash and then put a relative path then
削减任何东西，然后如果您将其指向点斜线，然后放置相对路径，然后
it just uses local yeah yeah that's what you said you can just pull the repo you can just
它只是使用本地是的，是的
close the repo and and do your modifications right quickly it's it's it's very very nice that
关闭存储库，然后迅速进行修改，这是非常非常好
you can just provide a local path um exactly awesome awesome yeah and uh the whole kurtosa
您可以提供一条本地路径，嗯，真棒，是的，整个库尔托萨
setup is completely open source you can mess with kurtosis itself you can mess with uh test net
设置是完全开源的，您可能会弄乱峰度本身
definitions you can mess with basically anything you want to mess the whole stack open sourced
定义您可能会弄乱基本上想弄乱整个堆栈开源的任何东西
okay awesome awesome yeah thank you barry i think we can go on with the presentation and
好吧，太棒了，谢谢你巴里，我想我们可以继续演讲
it back to the questions perfect so the next one's a bit of a loaded topic um shadowfox
它回到了完美的问题，所以下一个是一个加载的主题um shadowfox
so you might have heard of shadowfox both in um the context of the merge as well as almost
因此，您可能已经在合并的背景下听说过Shadowfox
everything single ethereum upgrade that happens so shadow forks allows us to
发生的所有单一以太坊升级都会发生，因此阴影叉使我们能够
what it essentially does is you take a main network and then you fork it but you fork it
从本质上讲，您要做一个主网络，然后分叉，但要分叉
just in a small subset of nodes leaving the main network untouched as a result you inherit the
仅在一小部分节点中，因此您继承了主要网络
state of the main network but if you configure a fork then you're forking in your tiny shadow chain
主网络的状态，但是如果您配置了叉子，那么您就在微小的影子链中分叉
There's a nice visual in the next graph, but before we get there, doing this setup helps us
下一个图中有一个不错的视觉效果，但是在我们到达那里之前，进行此设置有帮助我们
understand and check compatibility across clients through the entire life cycle. So
在整个生命周期中了解和检查客户之间的兼容性。所以
you are inherently building a mainnet block. It's just that Ethereum mainnet, for example,
您本质地构建了一个主网块。例如，以太坊的主网
rejects your block because it's non-canonical. But you've gone through the process of building
拒绝您的区块，因为它是非典型的。但是您已经完成了建设的过程
mainnet block which is the important part for my testing perspective. This allows us to check a lot
主网块，这是我测试观点的重要组成部分。这使我们可以检查很多
of assumptions so for example when we were doing blob testing if for whatever reason building a
例如，例如，当我们进行斑点测试时，如果出于何种原因进行blob测试
blob and verifying that with a mainnet state size was infeasible we would have seen that here. This
Blob并验证Mainnet状态大小是不可行的，我们会在这里看到这一点。这
was extremely valuable in the merge because we would set an override ttd that just happened a
合并非常有价值，因为我们将设定一个刚刚发生的替代TTD
a few blocks in the future. And when we do that, you're essentially simulating the merge
将来有几个街区。当我们这样做时，您实际上是在模拟合并
without touching main net Ethereum, which was very powerful to have as a testing tool.
没有接触主要的以太坊，这是一种非常强大的测试工具。
You're stress testing the client, this will be as close to main net as possible,
您正在压力测试客户，这将尽可能接近主网，
or as close to whatever network you're shadow forking as possible. So it comes with all of
或尽可能靠近您的任何网络分叉。所以它带有所有
those assumptions. Because of the way peer-to-peer works, you still stay peered to the main network
那些假设。由于点对点的工作方式，您仍然凝视着主要网络
for a significant amount of time. So you're still importing transaction load. So if mainnet Ethereum
大量时间。因此，您仍在导入交易负载。因此，如果Mainnet以太坊
has a hundred something transactions that are happening in a block, your ShadowFork also has
有一百件事在一个街区中发生的交易，您的Shadowfork也有
those transactions included. Not all of them probably, but there are some intricacies as to
包括这些交易。并非所有人都可能
they won't get included the same way but fundamentally they are included which is
它们不会以相同的方式被包括在内，但从根本上讲，它们包括在内
really really useful for stress testing how a network performs and uh yeah you're controlling
对于压力测试网络的性能真的很有用，是的，您正在控制
the entire validator set so you can take care of how the network needs to be and it acts as a
整个验证器集，因此您可以照顾网络的需要，并且它充当
release test so this is kind of the last stage of the testing devnet testnet cycle that we see
发布测试，因此这是我们看到的测试DEVNET测试网络周期的最后阶段
it's going to work as expected.
它将按预期工作。
So I'm going to preface this with simple in principle.
因此，我将原则上简单地对此进行序言。
It is simple, but it is a bit of a hard-ish concept
这很简单，但这有点像是一个硬性的概念
to grok in the beginning.
一开始就gro吟着。
So what you do is also ignore that it's using Girly.
因此，您要做的是忽略它正在使用Girly。
I haven't updated my slides.
我没有更新幻灯片。
It should be Polsky or Sopolia by now,
到目前为止，应该是波尔斯基或索波里亚
but yeah, all right, it's pretty much the same.
但是，是的，好的，几乎是一样的。
So it's pretty much the same.
所以几乎一样。
earlier by now but um yeah or ephemera but um yeah for now let's talk about girly you take the
到现在为止
girly genesis file you can find this in github slash eth dash clients there's a repository
Girly Genesis文件您可以在GitHub Slash Eth dash客户端中找到此存储库
uh there for each testnet where all the genesis files exist i modify the genesis file so forget
嗯，每个testnet都在所有Genesis Files存在的位置，我修改了Genesis文件，所以忘记了
this is genesis.json and I add a fork timestamp. So I say petra timestamp colon
这是Genesis.json和我添加了一个叉时间戳。所以我说佩特拉时间戳结肠
one hour from now. Now I set up a new beacon chain with validators which also has the
从现在起一个小时。现在，我建立了一个带有验证器的新的信标连锁店，也有
Electra fork configured at the same exact timestamp and the deposit contract points
Electra叉在相同的精确时间戳和存款合同点配置
to the earlier girly chain right so now what you've done is you have a subset of validators
到较早的少女链，所以现在您所做的就是您有一部分验证器
in a new beacon chain that understand when the fork is happening you have a subset of execution
在一条新的信标链中，了解叉子发生何时发生
nodes with your modified genesis json file that think a fork is supposed to happen at some time
带有修改的Genesis JSON文件的节点，认为应该在某个时候发生叉子
no other golly node in the network has this configuration just your subset so when this
网络中没有其他Golly节点只有此配置，因此
timestamp is hit, so in this case when TTD was hit, the canonical chain, the
时间戳被击中，因此在这种情况下，当TTD击中时，规范链，
girly chain that you or me or anyone else is using, just continues as if
您或我或其他任何人正在使用的少女链，只是继续好像
nothing happened. But my local nodes with this modified girly config will think a
什么都没有发生。但是我使用此修改后的Girly配置的本地节点会认为
fork has happened, so they will execute the fork code. And since the EL just
叉子已经发生了，因此他们将执行叉子代码。而且由于El只是
builds the block when the CL tells it to and the CL is configured to build a block with this fork
当CL告诉它并配置CL时，将构建块
timestamp it will build on top of the last canonical girly block but this new curly block
时间戳它将建立在最后一个规范的少女块之上，但是这个新的卷曲块
is invalid in the main chain because it was built by a validator that no one in the main chain knows
在主链中是无效的
or recognizes but in my controlled validator set all of them no one recognize that validator so
或识别但在我的受控验证器设置中，所有人都没有人识别该验证者
they accept it. So what I've essentially done is forked the EL to build on top of the girly state
他们接受。因此，我本质上所做的就是派遣EL建立在少女状态的顶部
but just for my subset of validators. No one else has any indication of this.
但仅仅是我的验证者子集。没有人有任何迹象。
This new chain builds on top until infinity. Everyone who has a balance on girly will also
这个新的链子建立在无限的基础上。每个在少女上保持平衡的人也会
have a balance on this shadow fork. Some intricacies of course but all of it is essentially
在这个阴影叉上保持平衡。当然，一些复杂性，但这本质上都是
the same you're building on top of a existing network there's some peering complexities on top
您在现有网络之上构建的与您构建的一样
there's some mempool complexities on top i won't really go into that over here but you would stay
最重要的是有一些mempool复杂性，我不会真正进入这里，但是您会留下来
peered you would still fetch from the mempool for a certain amount of time slowly the state
凝视您仍然会从孟买的一定时间慢慢地从孟买那里获取
will continue to diverge because you're allocating transactions in different orders your
由于您正在按照不同的订单分配交易，因此将继续分歧
balances go out of sync after a while and then you stop peering with the main network and then
一段时间后，余额失去同步，然后您停止与主网络凝视，然后
ShadowFork is just it's own thing and will continue until you shut it down.
Shadowfork只是它自己的事，将继续直到您关闭它。
But for that period of time where it stays connected to the main network it's very very
但是在那一段时间内，它一直连接到主网络，这非常非常
valuable. And based on most testing this period of time is not trivial it stays like two days,
有价值的。基于大多数测试，这段时间并不小，它停留在两天的时间里，
three days depending on the size of your network and number of transactions and what you do with
三天，取决于您的网络大小和交易数量以及您的工作
this ShadowFork and so on. I know it was quick after the previous question session but usually
这个影子福克等。我知道在上一个问题会议之后很快，但通常
ShadowFox, since it's a biggish topic, I do want to stop for questions before we talk about what
ShadowFox，由于这是一个大主题，所以我想在谈论什么之前先停止提问
tools we have and what you can play around with in the testing world.
我们拥有的工具以及在测试世界中可以玩的东西。
Right, thank you Pari. So ShadowFox are very exciting, I love to follow them and see what
是的，谢谢Pari。所以Shadowfox非常令人兴奋，我喜欢跟随他们，看看什么
nodes drop off and it just gives us this exciting feeling about getting to the
节点下降了，这给了我们这种令人兴奋的感觉
it's always like a little moon lounge or something like that.
它总是像一个小月亮休息室或类似的东西。
I'm waiting for some questions to come in.
我正在等待一些问题进来。
Maybe while we're waiting, there's a link I've sent,
也许当我们在等待时，我发送了一个链接，
and you could open this link, and then I
您可以打开此链接，然后我
can showcase what is happening.
可以展示正在发生的事情。
So you can actually, we've added ShadowFox to OpsCore,
因此，您实际上可以，我们将Shadowfox添加到OpScore中，
fox to kurtosis so you can do like a one-line shadow fork just with the kurtosis command
狐狸到峰度，因此您可以像单行的阴影叉一样，只需使用峰度命令
and we do this with vocal um on a ci on a nightly basis so i talk about this later as well and i
我们每晚都会用CI进行声音UM进行此操作，所以我以后也谈论此事，我
think i've linked it later in the slide maybe since we're up here or you can open the link
认为我稍后在幻灯片中链接了它，也许是因为我们在这里或您可以打开链接
so um what you see here is the kurtosis config um as you this was updated just three hours ago this
所以嗯，您在这里看到的是Kurtosis config um，因为您仅在三个小时前就更新了
This is a live testing system, right?
这是一个现场测试系统，对吗？
So Guillaume is working on rebasing the work code base
因此，Guillaume正在努力重新审议工作代码库
such that both the transition
如此的过渡
as well as work genesis happens in the same thing
以及创世记也发生在同一事物中
and it has a concept in it.
它有一个概念。
So this is the rebase that we are testing.
因此，这是我们正在测试的重新观察。
We've defined one time load star get
我们定义了一次负载星获得
and one time, this time it's both load star get,
有一次，这一次都是负载星，
you could also just change count two
您也可以更改二
and achieve the same thing.
并实现同样的事情。
I want Electra to happen at fort epoch 1, so this is when the work will transition actually
我希望Electra发生在Epoch Fort 1上，所以这是工作将实际上过渡的时候
happens.
发生。
And here, I'm doing network holeski-shadowfork-workl, and network sync base URL, and this, we're
在这里，我正在进行网络holeski-shadowfork-workl和网络同步基础URL，这是我们
running it locally, so we have an S3 bucket with the holeski snapshot.
在本地运行它，因此我们有一个带有Holeski快照的S3桶。
So what this does is, Kurtosis will go to this IP address and fetch the S3 bucket that
因此，这是什么是，Kurtosis将转到此IP地址并获取S3桶
has the entire holsky state it will then start geth with this holsky state
拥有整个霍尔斯基州
and it will have a vocal fork that happens at epoch one so the only part missing in this situation
它将有一个在一个时期发生的声叉，所以在这种情况下唯一缺少的部分
was how do i know the transition succeeded or not right um and just for some more sprinkling
是我怎么知道过渡成功或不正确，只是为了撒一些洒水
of clarity we do this on a kubernetes cluster so if you see global node selector um
明确的是，我们在kubernetes群集上执行此操作，因此，如果您看到全局节点选择器UM
that doesn't mean anything to anyone else except our Kubernetes instance it
除了我们的kubernetes实例之外，这对其他任何人都没有什么意义
will run this transition on one machine that knows how to access that IP address.
将在知道如何访问该IP地址的一台计算机上运行此过渡。
So we're running this other tool called Asserta and you might have seen this once or twice and
因此，我们正在运行另一种称为Asserta的工具，您可能已经看到一次或两次
in the future I will be going a bit deeper into what it does but what Asserta does is
将来，我会更深入地了解它的作用，但Asserta所做的是
it checks and asserts that a certain condition is true or false and in this case Asserta is
它检查并断言某个条件是真或错误，在这种情况下，Asserta是
is fetching this test definition,
正在获取此测试定义，
work will conversion check,
工作将转换检查，
and every epoch or so it checks
每个时期左右都可以检查
if the work or transition was a success.
如果工作或过渡是成功的。
So from the CI perspective,
因此从CI的角度来看，
what this looks like is once a day,
这是每天一次
I'm pulling the latest image from Guillaume's fork,
我正在从Guillaume的叉子中摘下最新图片，
I'm fetching the latest Holsky snapshot,
我正在获取最新的Holsky快照，
I'm going through the entire work or transition,
我正在完成整个工作或过渡，
and then Asserta will give me a tick or a cross
然后Asserta会给我一个tick或十字架
in GitHub CI that tells me if the transition
在GitHub CI中告诉我是否过渡
a success last night or not um you can also trigger this manually so if i've made a big change
昨晚的成功或不嗯，您也可以手动触发此功能，因此，如果我做出了很大的更改
and before i merge in a pr i want to make sure that it's working i can do this and this is just
在我合并PR之前，我想确保它可以正常工作，我可以做到这一点，这只是
an example of work right there's no reason that um this cannot happen otherwise so you can also
一个工作的一个例子，没有理由不可能发生这种情况，否则您也可以
run this locally on your machine if you don't specify a network sync base url you're just going
如果您没有指定网络同步基础URL，则在计算机上本地运行此操作
to sync a holesky node locally it's not a big deal it'll just take more time so you probably want to
在本地同步一个holesky节点，这没什么大不了的，只需花费更多的时间，所以您可能想
add a bigger genesis delay but 100 seconds is enough for a local network to pull a snapshot so
添加更大的起源延迟，但100秒就足以让本地网络拉动快照，因此
we're we're running it with that
我们正在运行它
awesome thank you very much pari for showing us this um because it was there was a question
非常感谢您向我们展示了这个UM，因为有一个问题
there like what is the tooling to run shadow for it so you just yeah yeah so there's one example
那里像什么工具可以为它运行阴影，所以你只是是的，所以有一个示例
there and maybe there's another quick example it should be yes so I will send
那里，也许还有另一个快速示例，应该是，所以我会发送
you another link one second so there's another link if you could open this
您另一个链接一秒钟，如果您可以打开此链接
mario
马里奥
yeah so this is our um ci runner for um for kurtosis itself and we want to test that
是的，所以这是我们的UM CI跑步者，用于UM kurtosis本身，我们想测试
we're not breaking any functionality so we've just defined a wide range of things that you
我们没有破坏任何功能，所以我们只是定义了您的广泛的内容
can do with kurtosis and then the ci just runs it on before a pr um so if you ever need examples for
可以使用峰度，然后CI在PR um之前将其运行，因此，如果您需要示例
how to configure a certain thing this is the place to look and for example you can see hoski shadow
如何配置某个东西这是值得的地方，例如，您可以看到Hoski Shadow
fork work no run a bit up in the hitch hitch yeah that so here you're looking at uh or maybe go back
叉子工作在挂钩上没有跑步，是的
and look at the next example uh so without work yes so this example is where uh you are simply
并查看下一个示例嗯，所以不工作是，所以这个示例就是你在哪里
doing a husky shadow fork that will run the latest version of get teku that's it there's no complexity
做一个沙哑的影子叉，将运行最新版本的Get Teku，这是没有复杂性的
and you have to of course set denkoon for kipok is zero because the whole ski network has already had
当然，您必须为Kipok设置Denkoon，因为整个滑雪网络已经拥有
denkoon um and then this will spin up a explorer for you that's that's all this file is doing so
denkoon um，然后这将为您旋转一个探险家，这就是所有文件
So you can play around with ShadowFox all you want,
因此，您可以随心所欲地玩Shadowfox，
single one-liner, you can override the images
单个单线，您可以覆盖图像
if you want to test your changes,
如果您想测试更改，
you can, yeah, do a lot of things,
是的，可以做很多事情，
and we also support Ephemery.
我们也支持Ephemery。
Yeah, you can, by the way,
是的，你可以，顺便说一句
also use Kurtosis to sync a live network.
还使用峰度来同步实时网络。
So if you go back to Ephemery,
因此，如果您回到Ephemery，
this will spin up all of these participants
这将使所有这些参与者旋转
and configure them to sync
并将它们配置为同步
to the latest iteration of ephemerly.
最新的迭代迭代。
Nothing else is needed, you sync to ephemerly
不需要别的，您可以同步到短片
and that's it, you can change ephemerly to be mainnet,
就是这样，您可以更改以成为主网，
I really don't recommend mainnet
我真的不推荐主网
because kurtosis is a local testing tool,
因为峰度是一种本地测试工具，所以
it's not meant for mainnet level,
这并不是要用于主网级别，
one terabyte node, your laptop will get filled up,
一个Terabyte节点，您的笔记本电脑会填满，
we only do mainnet on kubernetes,
我们只在Kubernetes上进行主网，
but you can do polsky, sepolia, whatever it is,
但是你可以做波尔斯基，塞波利亚，无论它是什么，
and it will sync that network that you specify.
它将同步您指定的网络。
if you do so the naming convention we also try to standardize things so it's always network name
如果您这样做的命名约定，我们也会尝试标准化事物，因此它始终是网络名称
dash shadow fork if you want to do dash shadow fork and then if you put vocal after that then
破折号阴影叉如果您想做dash shadow fork，然后在那之后发声
there's some genesis magic that happens that uses the vocal genesis information
发生了一些创世纪的魔法，它使用了声乐创世纪信息
yeah awesome yeah yeah thanks much it's very interesting uh beginning to the
是的，很棒的是的，非常感谢，非常有趣的是
package repo so there are some questions on on Shadow forks how do we define
包装储备金，因此在阴影叉上有一些问题，我们如何定义
successful transition it's simply clients not failing up but you have some
成功的过渡只是客户没有失败，但是您有一些
to the definitions of tests that you measured um usually for us the transition success right now
按照您通常为我们测量的测试的定义，现在过渡成功
is just if all the nodes are at the same head and if the the we're working with the gets guys to add
只是如果所有节点都处于同一头部，并且我们正在与Get Guys一起工作
an api to know when the transition is done um and then we yeah we just wait for them to all be on
知道过渡何时完成的API，然后我们是的，我们只等待它们都在
the same head and for the logs i think to not show that it's the transaction in progress or something
我认为同一头和日志中，这是正在进行的交易或其他
But yeah, we want to make that configurable via API so that you can just query the API
但是，是的，我们想通过API进行配置，以便您可以查询API
and it says transition in progress or transition completed.
它说正在进行的过渡或过渡完成。
Thank you.
谢谢。
And a question, whether you can run a new validators, remove validators from ShadowForks,
还有一个问题，您是否可以运行新验证器，从Shadowforks中删除验证器，
whether it's further testing that you do?
您是否正在进行进一步的测试？
Could you repeat that?
你能再说一遍吗？
If you run new validators?
如果您运行新验证器？
So yeah, if you after the Shadowfork, whether it's one of the tests you do or you can do
是的，如果您在影子之后，无论是您参加的测试之一还是可以做的测试之一
is like doing it deposit it up in your yes.
就像这样做，将其存入您的是。
So I will talk about that particular question when I'm introducing it to you guys.
因此，当我向大家介绍它时，我会谈论这个特定的问题。
But for now, the answer is yes.
但是目前，答案是肯定的。
And I will show you how.
我会告诉你如何。
Okay, awesome.
好吧，很棒。
Awesome.
惊人的。
Thank you so much.
太感谢了。
There were some questions for demoing the issue with Kurtosis,
有一些问题，以调查峰度的问题，
but it's a log, so maybe we can leave it for later.
但这是一个日志，所以也许我们可以稍后再留下来。
Yeah.
是的。
Kurtosis guys also have a Discord.
Kurtosis的家伙也有不和谐。
They have a product support page.
他们有一个产品支持页面。
Please feel free to put stuff there.
请随时放在那里。
Because we actively change stuff,
因为我们积极改变了东西，所以
sometimes we also break things.
有时我们也会破坏东西。
But we try as much as possible not to break.
但是我们尽可能地尝试不破裂。
Awesome Pari, go ahead and we will get to the questions.
很棒的帕里，继续前进，我们将解决问题。
I think we have roughly about half an hour for the rest of the calls.
我认为我们的剩下的电话大约有大约半小时。
That should be enough for finishing questions.
这应该足以完成问题。
Okay, so overview about handy tools.
好的，因此概述了方便的工具。
We have a website, ethpandaops.io.
我们有一个网站EthpandaOps.io。
visit the website pretty self-explanatory the there's a tool there's a tools page on the top
访问网站非常不言自明该工具在顶部有一个工具页面
right you can see all the tools that we maintain as well as all the tools that we um that we have
是的，您可以看到我们维护的所有工具以及我们拥有的所有工具
along with some blog posts on how to use them and more are coming there's an asserter blog post
除了一些有关如何使用它们的博客文章，还有更多的博客文章
coming up this week next week at this time all the code bases for every single tool we build
下周本周即将到来，我们构建的每个工具的所有代码库
can be found in github everything is open source except for our logic is the tool is always open
可以在github中找到一切都是开源的，除了我们的逻辑是工具始终打开
sourced the config depending on if there's secrets or anything might not be open source but every
根据是否有秘密或其他任何可能不是开源的配置，而是每个配置
single tool every single test we have is open source from a licensing perspective we tend to
单个工具从许可的角度来看，我们拥有的每个测试都是开源的
use mit sometimes it may be gpl agpl but 99 of the time is mit so feel free to fork away feel free to
使用麻省理工学院有时可能是GPL AGPL
make PRs, add features. We're very happy when people add features. Yeah, also happy to modify
制作PR，添加功能。当人们添加功能时，我们非常高兴。是的，也很乐意修改
our tools to support anyone else. We often, the tools get reused by other networks. They get used
我们支持其他任何人的工具。我们经常，工具被其他网络重新使用。他们被用了
by L1s, L2s. Some of the DVT guys like Obal also use some of the tools. So we try to accommodate
由L1S，L2S。像Obal这样的一些DVT家伙也使用了一些工具。所以我们试图容纳
everyone's needs so that there's also better maintenance. That's how you build an ecosystem
每个人的需求，以便还可以更好地维护。这就是您建立生态系统的方式
around things rather than everyone building their own thing in silos um there's some reading for you
周围而不是每个人都在孤岛上建立自己的东西，嗯
guys and i will make sure to also put this later in uh some some talk or copy it around but there's
伙计们和我将确保稍后将其放在一些聊天中或复制时，但是有
a testing overview doc so both mario and i spent some time over the last week compiling it it is
一个测试概述文档，所以马里奥和我在上周花了一些时间来编译它
not exhausted yet but we are getting there it aims to define every single major testing tool that we
还没有用尽，但我们到达那里的目的是定义我们
have as well as who the maintainer is, what the tool does, and what layer of the stack the tool
具有谁是维护者，工具的作用以及堆叠的哪一层
is touching or testing. So please have a look at this one. As we go into Pectra,
正在接触或测试。所以请看看这个。当我们进入Pectra时，
we're also going to use this testing overview doc to try and understand what order we should test
我们还将使用此测试概述文档尝试并了解我们应该测试的顺序
things to coordinate a bit better between the different teams if you're interested in testing
如果您有兴趣测试，则可以在不同团队之间更好地协调一点
in itself find a project start contributing keep an eye out on ith r d interop usually
本身发现一个项目开始贡献一个项目，通常会关注Ith r d Interop
you might notice oh this is hard this is difficult does anyone know how to do this test
您可能会注意到哦，这很难
pick it up make a tool make a pr to an existing tool um add support for a new fork usually when
捡起它的工具使现有工具的公关通常增加对新叉的支持，通常是
neofock is defined there's like a list of prs we have to do some for some libraries some for
Neofock的定义是我们必须为某些库做一些PR的列表
some genesis tools some for tooling uh help us make those prs that's a great way to learn about
某些用于工具的创世纪工具可以帮助我们使这些PRS成为学习的好方法
a neofock so the first tool big one that i'm going to talk about was kurtosis so we've covered it i
一个新所库奇
think in quite extensive detail so i won't be going more into kurtosis uh please have a look
想一想的详细思考，所以我不会更多地涉足峰度嗯，请看看
at the github test join the it are the ethereum kato sorry the kurtosis discord chat uh server
在GitHub测试中加入它是以太坊Kato对不起的kurtosis Discord Chat UH服务器
in case you have questions uh they have a great support team um yeah like i said everything is
如果您有疑问，他们有一个很好的支持团队UM是的，就像我说的一切一样
open sourced feel free to use it as much as you want template devnets so i did mention this the
开源可以随意使用模板Devnets随意使用它，所以我确实提到了
template devnets uh repository is combining all of these different ansible terraform as well as
模板Devnets UH存储库正在结合所有这些不同的Ansible Terraform以及
Genesis files and all of this into one coherent repository. So GitHub has this feature where
创世纪文件和所有这些都成为一个连贯的存储库。因此，Github具有此功能
you can fork a repo out of a template or it's kind of like implement a template, right?
您可以从模板中分配存储库，也可以像实现模板一样，对吗？
So if you go to the template test net, there should be a button somewhere that says use this
因此，如果您转到模板测试网络，则应在某处说使用此按钮
template. And what that will do is it will create a new repository using that template in your
模板。那将要做的是它将在您的模板中创建一个新的存储库
namespace and we often do this for example if you go to work with dev nets on the top somewhere
命名空间，我们通常会这样做
it will say forked from template test net or part of template test net thing so if you ever want to
它会说从模板测试网或模板测试网的一部分中分叉，所以如果您想
know the entire diff between our template and workl just make a pr between main and main and
了解我们的模板和工作之间的整个差异，只是在主和主之间和
you will see all the changes required for buckle testing um this is very useful if you want to
您将看到带扣测试所需的所有更改，如果您想
run nodes on a larger scale if you want to run your own ethereum nodes so i run ethereum nodes
如果您想运行自己的以太坊节点，则在更大范围内运行节点，所以我运行以太坊节点
at home we run ethereum nodes in the office uh we use this exact infrastructure for doing all of it
在家里，我们在办公室运行以太坊节点，我们使用此确切的基础设施来完成所有操作
it's very mainnet compatible it's very safe feel free to use it there's not much magic that happens
它非常兼容，这是非常安全的，请随时使用它，没有太多的魔法发生
this is this level of testing you normally get to once the local testing tools are inadequate
这是一旦本地测试工具不足，您通常会进行的测试水平
it tends to happen a bit later in the fork process so if anyone is questioning it i would say spend
它往往会在叉子过程中发生一点，因此，如果有人质疑它，我会说花
more time on kurtosis because with template testnet you need to know what ansible is you
更多的时间峰度，因为使用模板testnet，您需要知道您是什么可接管的
need to know what terraform is before you can actually start doing stuff and if you for example
需要知道什么是Terraform，然后才能真正开始做事，例如
spin up a terraform a bunch of cloud instances which terraform that's also going to cost you
旋转一个Terraform一堆云实例，Terraform也将花费您
money whereas in kurtosis the worst thing that can happen is that you have a docker container
钱，而在峰度中，最糟糕的事情可能是您有一个码头容器
running for one day too long. There's no risk involved there. So play around with template
跑步太久了。那里没有风险。所以玩模板
test net, especially if you're someone who's looking to get into a bit more DevOps-y role,
测试网，尤其是如果您是一个希望扮演更多Devops-y角色的人，
a bit more deep insight into how DevOps works, then this is the place to go.
对DevOps的工作原理有了更深入的了解，这是去的地方。
So now for the big one, Asserta. So you can find the Asserta repository under ithpandaops.
因此，对于大个子来说，Asserta。因此，您可以在IthpandaOps下找到Asserta存储库。
The idea of Asserta is it asserts a network level expectation.
Asserta的想法是它主张网络级别的期望。
Example, can a network handle deposits?
例如，网络可以处理存款吗？
Can it handle a transaction that has every opcode being called?
它可以处理每个opcode都被调用的交易吗？
Can it handle a reorg?
它可以处理reorg吗？
That's the question that Asserta tries to answer.
这就是Asserta试图回答的问题。
And it's a generalized testing tool, so you can use this for assertions on any network.
它是一种广义测试工具，因此您可以将其用于任何网络上的断言。
you just have to define what the assertion is, what the health check or what is correct wrong is,
您只需要定义什么是断言，健康检查或正确的错误是什么，
and then you have to run Assertor with that test definition, and you have to point it at which
然后，您必须使用该测试定义进行断言，并且必须指出它
nodes to check. So when you do these three things, Assertor will check those nodes based on your
节点要检查。因此，当您做这三件事时，主张会根据您的
definition, and it will assert the definition assertion that you've given over there.
定义，它将断言您在那儿给出的定义断言。
So the example that I was mentioning was the transitional success. So ideally, we'd like to
因此，我提到的例子就是过渡成功。因此，理想情况下，我们想
it in a place where I can just query all the APIs and the API says transition success equals
它在我可以查询所有API的地方，API表示过渡成功等于
to a transition equals complete and then Asserta will say okay the work transition was defined as
过渡等于完整，然后Asserta会说好的工作过渡被定义为
when this API call returns true then it's done and you can add a timeout saying if it doesn't happen
当此API调用返回正确时，它已经完成，您可以添加一个超时说明是否没有发生
within one hour then it's a fail and Asserta will say okay it didn't happen within one hour
在一小时内就失败了，Asserta会说好的，它没有在一小时内发生
let's return a fail. Asserta can be interacted with via the API, so you can run it and then
让我们退回失败。可以通过API与Asserta进行交互，因此您可以运行它，然后
configure tests. This is very useful in some cases like Kubernetes or if you have public instances,
配置测试。在某些情况下，这非常有用，例如Kubernetes或您有公共实例，
you can also run it at runtime with all the tests defined, you can fetch information from
您还可以在定义的所有测试中运行时运行它，您可以从
Asserta via its API, you can fetch information via its logs. It's kind of like this middleware
通过其API asserta，您可以通过其日志获取信息。有点像这个中间件
that does everything you need it to do for ensuring a network behaves as it should behave
您需要做的一切，以确保网络的行为表现
because the timeouts are also configurable, we do deposit tests with this, we do withdrawal
因为超时也可以配置
tests with this, we do slashing tests with this, so I can define how a Sorter creates a
对此进行测试，我们确实对此进行了削减测试，因此我可以定义分类器如何创建一个
slashable condition and then it executes the slashable condition for me and it makes sure
可靠的条件，然后为我执行可倾斜的条件，并确保
that every node has accepted the slam. So you know that when and if this happens on a real network,
每个节点都接受了猛击。因此，您知道何时以及如果发生在真实网络上，
that all of these are working. You can also configure something like, make sure that every
所有这些都在起作用。您也可以配置类似的东西，请确保每个
node in my local dev net has proposed a block at least once. And this is really useful for
我本地开发网络中的节点至少提出了一个块。这真的很有用
fork testing, because you want to make sure that you're not breaking attestations, that you're not
分叉测试，因为您想确保自己没有破坏证明，所以
breaking proposals, that you're not breaking the fundamental parts of what makes a network.
打破建议，即您不会打破建立网络的基本部分。
Yeah, so you can do a lot of these things. And we also do, we're currently focusing on trying to get
是的，所以您可以做很多这些事情。而且我们也这样做，我们目前致力于尝试
every validator client compatible with every beacon node. So that's a quite a big matrix.
每个验证器客户端与每个信标节点兼容。所以这是一个很大的矩阵。
And that should be compatible with every execution layer node. And you can see in, I think in
这应该与每个执行层节点兼容。我认为您可以看到
kurtosis already in the page we have a matrix of which combinations don't work you might see
页面上的峰度已经有一个矩阵，您可能会看到哪些组合不起作用
some chatter about this on the interop channel as well um and we're slowly taking them off
在Interop频道上也对此有些chat不休，我们正在慢慢将它们取下
one by one we're getting there but we primarily use assorter to figure this out um it can also
我们一一我们到达那里，但我们主要使用Assorter来弄清楚这一点，也可以
be run locally so like i showed you earlier via kurtosis it has a certain built-in or you can
在本地运行，就像我早些时候通过kurtosis向您展示的那样，它具有一定的内置，或者您可以
integrate it into a ci so there's an assertive github action and you can use this github action
将其集成到CI中，因此有一个自信的github动作，您可以使用此github动作
in your repository that's what we've done with the vocal uh devnets repository so that just calls
在您的存储库中，这就是我们对Vocal uh devnets存储库所做的工作
a sort of points it at a in that example a kubernetes cluster it does a shadow fork and
在那个示例中，一种指向kubernetes群集的某种指向它的阴影叉和
that shadow fork as seen here that shadow fork does the local conversion check the test as you
阴影叉在这里可以看出，阴影叉进行本地转换检查测试
might have guessed can also be a local definition it doesn't have to be a remote definition it could
可能已经猜到也可能是本地定义，它不一定是远程定义
be a github gist it can be a notes on hackmd it can be whatever you want it to be so it's a very
成为github要点，可以是hackmd上的笔记，这可以是你想要的，所以这是一个非常
very generalized testing tool please use a Sauter as much as possible it's a
非常概括的测试工具，请尽可能多地使用索特尔
relatively new tool it's only a few months old at this point so it hasn't
相对较新的工具，此时只有几个月的历史了，因此还没有
gotten the prime time that it deserves but we're hoping to use it more and for
获得了应有的黄金时间，但我们希望更多地使用它
those of you who attended Mario's call you might notice that it has a lot of
那些参加马里奥打电话的人可能会注意到它有很多
overlap with hive so hive also does a lot of assertions right it says I give
与Hive重叠，因此Hive也做了很多断言，我说我给
this transaction this is the EVM state transition that needs to happen did that
这笔交易这是需要发生的EVM状态转变。
happen on this node. Hive does this. So why did we build a whole new tool to do this?
发生在此节点上。蜂巢这样做。那么，为什么我们要构建一个全新的工具来做到这一点呢？
Because the way Hive is architected it's very very nice for single nodes. It is possible in Hive
因为蜂巢的构建方式对于单节节点来说非常好。在蜂巢中有可能
to do inter-orb multiple node testing it's just more cumbersome and Hive is built such that each
要进行孔间的多个节点测试，它只是更加笨拙，并且建立了蜂巢
test takes a very short-ish duration of time. You can configure it to do a longer duration it's not
测试需要很短的时间。您可以将其配置为更长的时间
made for it. Asserta doesn't have those assumptions. A deposit, for example, on a perfect
为此。 Asserta没有这些假设。例如，一个押金，完美
network level thing takes, what, half a day to process through the queue. Hive, it's not
网络级别需要半天通过队列处理。蜂巢，不是
necessarily multi-threaded in the same way, so it might, depending on how you configure it, get stuck
必然以相同的方式进行多线程，因此可能会根据您的配置方式，被卡住
on that one deposit until it's processed by the network before it moves on to the next test. So
在该存款上，直到网络处理到下一个测试之前。所以
Asserta is just built from the ground up to work in a network-wide scenario.
Asserta刚刚从头开始建造，以在整个网络的情况下工作。
So the way my mental model works is Hive is what we will always use
因此，我的心理模型的工作方式是我们将永远使用的方式
for single-node black box-level testing,
对于单个节点黑盒级测试，
and Asserta is what we'll use for network-level testing,
Asserta是我们将用于网络级测试的方法，
where the network itself is a black box,
网络本身是黑匣子，
and I just want to assert behaviors in a network.
我只想在网络中宣称行为。
So they're very synergetic.
因此，它们非常协同。
it's energetic ideally hive finds all the critical bugs before it gets to the
理想情况下，这是充满活力
assortment level but if it does then it's also nice to have these two tools
分类水平，但如果这样做也很高兴拥有这两个工具
that can kind of compare outputs and say hey this should have failed in hive why
这可以比较输出，并说嘿，这应该在蜂巢中失败了
didn't it or this should have failed in assort or why didn't it still give us
不是还是应该失败的，或者为什么还没有给我们
this level of flexibility that that we can benefit from so please try this out
我们可以从中受益的这种灵活性，因此请尝试一下
So let us know if you have feedback, and we'll be announcing it more widely over the next weeks.
因此，让我们知道您是否有反馈，我们将在接下来的几周内宣布它。
Now for a bit smaller CLI-level tools.
现在，要使用一些较小的Cli级工具。
Some of you might be tempted to work on the fork choice.
你们中有些人可能很想在叉子选择上工作。
May whichever DAT you believe in support you in that endeavor.
可以在这一努力中相信您支持您的哪个DAT。
it's a difficult field and it's very difficult to understand what is going on with fork choice
这是一个困难的领域，很难理解叉子选择正在发生的事情
hence we built forky so forky is a fork choice visualizer it relies on the beacon node
因此，我们建立了borky
standard api so every single node supports it and what this does is it connects to nodes that
标准API，因此每个节点都支持它，而这是它连接到节点
you've linked it to and it visualizes fork choice you can also upload a fork choice from your local
您已经将其链接到，它可视化叉子选择您还可以从当地上传叉子选择
node and it will visualize this for you it sometimes helps with fork choice debugging
节点，它将为您提供可视化，有时有助于叉子选择调试
to see the tree of what was built on what and what weight something had it really really helps
看到树木建立在什么和体重上的东西真正有帮助的树
in a critical situation this can run in uh as a binary as a docker file as a helen chart as
在危急情况下，这可以以二进制文件作为docker文件作为helen图表作为二进制
ansible under kurtosis as you see we support a wide range of things and if you're ever intrigued
如您所见，在峰度下，我们支持各种各样的事情，如果您有兴趣
what the forkchars and mainnet does please don't take the instance down by a thousand people
叉车和主网所做的一切请不要将实例放下一千人
calling it at the same time but let's see if the auto scaling works well go to this url and you
同时打电话给它，但让我们看看自动缩放是否效果很好
will see how the fork choice on ethereum looks exactly at this moment you will see tiny lines
将会看到以太坊上的叉子选择在这一刻，您会看到微小的线条
at the bottom as well those lines are snapshots that are being taken once every slot so you can
在底部，这些线路是每一个插槽一次拍摄的快照，以便您可以
also share that snapshot link with someone and it links to an s3 bucket so even one day later if you
还可以与某人共享快照链接，并且它链接到S3存储桶，因此甚至在一天之后，如果您
want to debug something it will load from that snapshot and it's a lot of
想要调试一些可以从该快照中加载的东西，这是很多
quality-of-life improvements we spend some time on. The next tool I want to
我们花了一些时间的生活质量改进。我要的下一个工具
talk about is Tracer it's still an active work in progress I don't know how
谈论示踪剂，这仍然是一项积极的工作，我不知道如何
many of you have worked with the trace API yet but it's not the most standard
你们中的许多人都已经与Trace API合作，但这不是最标准的
thing in the world and when there's a big mainnet incident, traces tend to be the first thing we go
世界上的事情，当有大型的主网事件时，痕迹往往是我们走的第一件事
to or one of the first things we go to see. So we have a mainnet tracer it connects to one of each
或我们要看的第一件事之一。因此，我们有一个连接到每个的主网示踪剂
EL and CL and what it does is every single block it traces it, uploads it there, every single slot
EL和CL以及它的作用是每个块它跟踪它，将其上传到那里，每个插槽
it gets the beacon SSE, the state SSE, it uploads it there. It has instructions on how to take the
它获取了Beacon SSE，State SSE，将其上传到那里。它有有关如何采用的说明
traces from two different ELs and then compare them to see if there's a diff. Ideally, in mainnet,
从两个不同的EL进行跟踪，然后比较它们以查看是否有差异。理想情况下，在主网，
there's zero diffs. But when there's an issue, the diff helps us find out where the problem was.
有零差异。但是，当存在问题时，差异可以帮助我们找出问题所在。
And with state.sse, what you can do is you can take the previous state, the next state,
借助state.sse，您可以做的是您可以采取以前的状态，下一个状态，
and then you can use a host of tools to go through this transition. Ideally, every single one of
然后，您可以使用许多工具进行此过渡。理想情况下，每一个
those tools gives you the same output. If it doesn't, you have a problem and you need to figure out why.
这些工具为您提供相同的输出。如果没有，您有问题，您需要弄清楚原因。
And this tool kind of is a tool that we hope to never use, but when you need to use it,
而这种工具是我们希望永远不会使用的工具，但是当您需要使用它时，
it's something we want to use. We had a blog post about this recently. And in the same form as
这是我们要使用的东西。我们最近有一篇博客文章。并以与
Checkpoint Z, the team has built this tool,
检查点Z，团队已经建立了此工具，
but ideally we would like the community to run it.
但是理想情况下，我们希望社区运行它。
We don't want to run this ourselves.
我们不想自己运行。
As an ethos, the ETH Panda Ops team
作为精神，Eth Panda Ops团队
tries to never run anything for mainnet
试图从未为mainnet运行任何东西
because we don't want to canonicalize what mainnet is.
因为我们不想将mainnet是什么。
That should be dependent on the community.
这应该取决于社区。
We tend to just run stuff for testnets.
我们倾向于只运行测试网络的东西。
We are running Tracer for mainnet
我们正在为mainnet运行示踪剂
purely until the network effects of community
纯粹直到社区的网络影响
running these tools builds up.
运行这些工具正在积累。
This really helps.
这确实有帮助。
So if you have a lot, then please do.
因此，如果您有很多，那就去做。
The next one is Dora.
下一个是多拉。
So Dora is a lightweight beacon chain explorer, extremely extendable.
因此，多拉（Dora）是一款轻巧的信标连锁探险家，非常可扩展。
So we have Dora for Verkle, we have Dora for Holsky, you have Dora for everything.
因此，我们有Verkle的Dora，我们为Holsky提供了Dora，您为所有事情都有Dora。
Even the beacon chain guys run Dora as a backup in case beacon chain has a problem.
即使是Beacon Chain Guys也将Dora作为备份，如果Beacon Chain有问题。
It gives you low-level access to the database.
它为您提供了对数据库的低水平访问。
so much so that you can it you can run dora and very often when we want to do some mev style
如此之多，以至于您可以经常运行Dora，并且经常想做一些MEV风格
analysis we just run like a sql query against the dora database and we get the information we want
分析我们只是像SQL查询一样对DORA数据库进行运行，我们获得了所需的信息
to do it's very extendable very useful please have a look easy to run and dora has a built-in
要做到这一点非常有用，请让外观易于运行，Dora具有内置
like fork visualizer so if you have 10 nodes it'll tell you if two of those nodes are forked
像叉可视化器一样，如果您有10个节点，它将告诉您是否有两个节点
or whatever you can do ELF or CLFox it does all the nice things the next one and last tool I'm
或您可以做的任何事情Elf或Clfox，它可以完成我的下一个和最后一个工具的所有美好事物
going to talk about today is xatu anyone who is really interested in data and data visualization
今天要谈论的是Xatu对数据和数据可视化真正感兴趣的人
should be paying attention to these two repositories the ethereum peer-to-peer
应该关注这两个存储库以太坊点对点
layer is notoriously hard to get visibility about there's a lot of noise to go through
众所周知，很难获得有关有很多噪音的可见性
There's millions of events that go through.
有数百万事件发生。
Okay, that's something different.
好的，那是不同的。
There's millions of events to go through.
有数百万事件需要进行。
There's literally every slot, a couple million
实际上每个插槽都有几百万
or a couple hundred thousand attestations that go through it.
或经历了数十万个证明。
So what we did is Zhaotu
所以我们所做的是Zhaotu
analyze or collect all of this data, puts it in a shared database,
分析或收集所有这些数据，将其放在共享数据库中，
And then you can use a tool like Grafana that visualizes this,
然后，您可以使用像Grafana这样的工具来可视化这一点，
but the database can also be queried directly.
但是数据库也可以直接查询。
All the data or almost all of the data that Zato has is open sourced.
Zato拥有的所有数据或几乎所有数据都是开源的。
We're still in the process of open sourcing whatever's left over.
我们仍在开放采购剩下的一切。
And in case you're someone who's interested in the data challenge
如果您是对数据挑战感兴趣的人
that the Ethereum Foundation's organizing right now,
以太坊基金会现在的组织
please have a look at the Zato data.
请查看Zato数据。
It might save you a lot of time from collecting your own.
它可以为您节省大量时间收集自己的时间。
The way it works is, we have these things called xatu sentries, so these sentries collect
它的工作方式是，我们有这些称为Xatu哨兵的东西，因此这些哨兵收集
to a consensus node, and it uses the event stream, it fetches the event stream, it annotates
共有节点，并使用事件流，它获取事件流，并注释
the data and pushes it to xatu server.
数据并将其推到XATU服务器。
There's another crawler that does some diskv5, diskv4 stuff, there's something else that
还有另一个爬网手做一些diskv5，diskv4的东西，还有其他东西
collects mempool data, all of this gets backfilled, put in xatu server, and this is persisted
收集MEMPOOL数据，所有这些都将重新填充，放入XATU服务器，这是持续存在的
I think we have over a year worth of main net data in this pipeline, a couple billion rows in it,
我认为我们在这条管道中拥有一年多的主要净数据，其中有数十亿，
there's a lot. And all of this gets ingested into a data pipeline. And the reason it goes into a data
有很多。所有这些都将摄入到数据管道中。以及它进入数据的原因
pipeline is the questions you want to answer are not apparent from the data, you might need to do
管道是您想回答的问题，从数据中不明显，您可能需要做
transformations, you might need to do some amount of analysis, right, and you want to canonicalize
转换，您可能需要进行一些分析，正确，并且您想进行规范化
these analyses so we have an entire data pipeline built for this already and the output of the data
这些分析，因此我们已经为此构建了整个数据管道以及数据的输出
pipeline can be graphs like this where you can see a heat map of when attestations arrive at which
管道可以是这样的图表
millisecond in which network you can see how long they took to propagate along the network so
毫秒在哪个网络上，您可以看到他们花了多长时间沿网络传播
something you might find interesting is usually there's a strong heat map at the four second mark
您可能会发现有趣的东西通常是在四秒标记处有一个很强的热图
because that's when there's a attestation deadline and proposals tend to go through then before that
因为那是有证明截止日期和提议在那之前往往会经过的时候
And you can also look at blob sidecars and when different nodes saw it.
而且，您还可以查看Blob Sidecars以及不同的节点看到它。
And you can create like a P95 metric for this to know,
您可以像p95度量一样创建，以了解，
okay, I have 100 nodes in 50 different locations.
好的，我在50个不同的位置有100个节点。
And 95% of them saw a particular number of blobs arrive
他们中有95％看到了特定数量的斑点到来
well under a certain time that we expect the network to handle in a healthy manner.
在一定时间内，我们期望网络以健康的方式处理。
This allows us to make really deep decisions on Ethereum,
这使我们能够就以太坊做出真正的决策，
how many blobs to have, how the propagation statistics look like, etc.
有多少个斑点，传播统计的外观，等等。
And the entire stack is reproducible on testnets.
并且整个堆栈在测试网络上都是可重现的。
We do reproduce it on testnets, and it helps us answer a lot of these questions.
我们确实在测试网上复制了它，它可以帮助我们回答很多此类问题。
One thing we're still working on is trying to automate more analyses.
我们仍在努力的一件事是试图自动进行更多的分析。
So you might notice in the ETH PandaOps blog,
因此，您可能会在Eth Pandaops博客中注意到
we have one manual analysis done for the mainnet and KuhnFork.
我们对主网和库恩福克进行了一项手动分析。
we're trying to analyze and figure out how to better get that kind of output without someone
我们正在尝试分析并弄清楚如何在没有某人的情况下更好地获得这种输出
having to sift through the data each time there's some answers to use stuff like local llm models to
每次都必须筛选数据时，都有一些答案可以使用本地LLM型号等内容
analyze the data still not really happy if someone wants to explore that side please do
分析数据仍然不满意，如果有人想探索该方面，请这样做
the data is all out there so yeah i think that's a great synergy that could exist
数据全部都在那里，是的，我认为这是一种很棒的协同作用
and what next um like i was mentioning i think in most of the call the highest value thing i
接下来的我要提到的是，我认为在大多数电话中，我的价值最高的东西我
would like you guys to take away is how to run your local devnet and how to do a prototype
希望你们能带走如何运行本地Devnet以及如何制作原型
so please at the bare minimum fork a client add hello world to the terminal output run
因此，请在最低限度的叉子上添加客户端向终端输出添加Hello World
kurtosis with your fork client and be happy that your name is printed out in the get logs
与您的叉子客户kurtosis，并为您的名字打印在Get Logs中
and that's just a gateway to get you into knowing how the system works into how you can extend it
这只是一个门户，让您知道系统如何运作如何扩展它
there was someone last year from the protocol fellowship who worked on
去年有协议奖学金的人从事
a version of i want to say epbs but i'm not particularly sure if it was epbs or not
我想说的EPB的一个版本，但我不太确定是否是EPB
and he used kurtosis extensively for his testing and once he was done with kurtosis for his testing
他广泛使用峰度进行测试，一旦他完成了峰度的测试
He also migrated the entire stack onto the girly network, I think.
我认为，他还将整个堆栈迁移到了Girly网络上。
And that helped give us a lot of insight into what works, what doesn't work.
这有助于我们了解什么有效，什么不起作用。
He worked with the researchers to do some analysis on how difficult the implementation might be,
他与研究人员合作，对实施的难度有多大分析，
what edge cases might exist and so on.
可能存在哪些边缘情况，依此类推。
And I do think that everyone should use tests and testing as a great starting point
而且我确实认为每个人都应该使用测试和测试作为一个很好的起点
because it's a really nice way to learn how Ethereum works.
因为这是学习以太坊如何工作的一种非常好的方法。
please again go through whatever mario has shown you guys in the last uh talks the testing team is
请再次通过Mario在最后一个UH谈话中向你们展示的任何事情
amazing they're very accommodating and we are really accommodating as well so if you feel like
令人惊讶的是，它们非常包容，我们也非常包容，所以如果您觉得
you want to contribute to any layer of the testing stack please do write tests write a sort of test
您想为测试堆栈的任何一层做出贡献
write hive tests write spec tests whatever they are and that gives you a new understanding how
编写Hive测试编写规格测试无论如何，这使您有了新的了解
of how ethereum works what the edge cases are so that when you're working on whatever you
以太坊如何工作的边缘案例是什么，以便当您从事任何工作时
work you want to work on you know what the entire space looks like and what
您想从事的工作您知道整个空间的外观以及什么
considerations you might want to have and thank you help us with testing the
您可能想拥有的注意事项，谢谢您帮助我们测试
next fork follow github follow me on Twitter and we hopefully it's left some
下一个叉子关注Github在Twitter上关注我，我们希望它留给我
time for questions it's great and it was a lot I it's it's why I was saying in
是时候提出问题了，这很棒，这是很多我，这就是为什么我在
the beginning that you became care of a cover house of these tools because
您开始照顾这些工具的封面房屋的开始，因为
There are just so many of them.
其中有很多。
And yeah, I just want to repeat what you said, it's one of the great ways to learn how it
是的，我只想重复您所说的话，这是了解它的好方法之一
works and just running all these tools, like connecting them to your client and seeing
工作并只是运行所有这些工具，例如将它们连接到您的客户并看到
the metrics and what is actually happening there.
指标以及那里实际发生的事情。
It's really great. And also, so what you said that you can avoid running it on the main
真的很棒。而且，您所说的话，您可以避免在主机上运行它
ad publicly. So, guys, if anybody wants to host this, feel free, I guess.
公开广告。所以，我想，如果有人想托管这一点，请自由。
it I'm actually I was actually running tracer on my note I was trying to figure
它实际上我实际上是在我的笔记上运行示踪剂，我想弄清楚
something out I did it but it I read it and maybe I should have hosted it's
我做了一些事情，但我读了它，也许我应该托管它
it's pretty cool to know yeah thank you Pari for everything it's it's been it's
知道是的，谢谢你的帕里很酷
been quite a lot so people like the domain question is it people want to see
很多人，所以像域问题这样的人是人们想看到的
you do some demos, some practical experiment.
您进行一些演示，一些实用的实验。
But I'm not sure whether we have time for that
但是我不确定我们是否有时间
and whether you are available.
以及您是否可用。
And you already mentioned many things
而且您已经提到了很多事情
that people can try themselves.
人们可以尝试自己。
I can, if you want, quickly run a kurtosis test on something
如果您愿意，我可以迅速对某些东西进行峰度测试
and show you guys how that looks,
并向你们展示看起来的样子，
if maybe that's the easiest first thing to do.
如果这是最简单的第一件事。
But if there's any other questions,
但是，如果还有其他问题，
Maybe you can do the questions before that.
也许您可以在此之前做问题。
Yeah, yeah.
是啊是啊。
All right.
好的。
Yeah, people wish for the practical experiment.
是的，人们希望进行实践。
Another question coming in.
另一个问题进来。
OK.
好的。
Yeah, people are asking about the Python specs,
是的，人们正在询问Python规格，
or the spec tests, whether you use them at some point here.
还是规格测试，无论您在某个时候使用它们。
And yeah.
是的。
For Python spec tests, so that tends
对于Python规格测试，因此
be more of individual so the way we kind of have defined or divided the territory so that we can
更多的是个人，因此我们定义或分裂领土的方式，以便我们可以
both specialize a bit more easily is anything that you can expect to be tested on a single node
两者都更容易地专业是您可以期望在一个节点上测试的任何内容
mario testing team uh python spec team they handle it anything that is expected to be tested at the
马里奥测试团队UH Python规格团队，他们处理的任何预期将在
interop level the eth panda ops team tests so that's ideally how we've defined them so i
Interop级别的ETH PANDA OPS团队测试，因此理想情况下我们已经定义了它们，所以我
personally rarely run spec tests. I help maintain some of the servers that run spec tests but
个人很少运行规格测试。我帮助维护一些运行规格测试的服务器，但是
otherwise I don't run the spec test myself. Right, it makes sense. I guess it's all like the
否则我不会自己运行规格测试。是的，这很有意义。我想这一切都像
progress where it comes from like specs and implementation that client themes and
从类似规格和实施的地方进步该客户主题和
statistics themselves and then it proves to be throughout so like you are already the other
统计本身，然后被证明是整个统计数据，所以就像您已经是另一个
side there. Just for the context because people are also asking about the
那里的一面。只是为了上下文，因为人们也在询问
mario's topic, I will just point you to the week four there, it's all it's all nicely explained
马里奥的话题，我将您指向第四周，这一切都很好地解释了
there. Cool. Okay, if someone wants to maybe see a small example, I can show a real-world use case
那里。凉爽的。好的，如果有人想看一个小例子，我可以显示现实世界中的用例
of a problem we had last week, and we are still sort of facing, but we wanted to see. So when you
在上周我们遇到的问题中，我们仍然面临着面对的，但我们想看看。所以当你
run this or when you ran this last week what would happen is the first version
运行此或上周跑步时，将发生的是第一个版本
the first participant was just a CL TeKu the default EL is geth works fine
第一位参与者只是一个cl teku，默认的el是geth效果很好
TeKu builds in the validator so the validator and beacon is in the same
Teku在验证器中构建，因此验证器和信标在相同
process this proposes blocks zero problems the next one is separate VC so
处理这提出了块零问题，下一个问题是单独的vc，所以
So in this one, you have a Teco beacon and a Teco validator client.
因此，在此中，您有一个Teco Beacon和一个TECO验证器客户端。
And this works fine as well.
而且这也很好。
It proposes blocks.
它提出了块。
It can attest.
它可以证明。
Everything is okay.
一切都可以。
But when I do separate VC and Snooper enabled, then it was failing.
但是，当我启用VC和Snooper分开时，它就会失败。
And we didn't know why.
我们不知道为什么。
And the reason it was failing is that the Teco beacon and validator client use a binary
失败的原因是teco信标和验证器客户端使用二进制
octet stream to communicate um whatever the payloads that they they want to communicate
八位位集流以通信UM他们想交流的有效载荷
and we have uh i might have to share a different screen
而且我们有嗯，我可能必须共享另一个屏幕
so we have
所以我们有
one second let me just share my entire screen yeah so uh yeah you guys should be able to see this
一秒钟让我只分享我的整个屏幕，是的，是的，你们应该能够看到这个
So we have this one tool that was built by each streamer called JSON-RPC-SNOOP. So JSON-RPC-SNOOP
因此，我们有一个由JSON-RPC-SNOOP构建的一个工具。所以JSON-RPC-SNOOP
is built in Rust and this tool was not able to understand a binary octet stream
是在生锈的
because when that was hit it was hitting edge case so you can see it tries to unwrap it and
因为当被击中时，它正在击中边缘案件，因此您可以看到它试图解开它，并且
that didn't work out and then it errored out and it crashed and it crashed and we weren't
那没有解决
able to figure out what was going on so the practical way we figured out what happened was
能够弄清楚发生了什么，所以我们弄清楚发生了什么的实用方法是
then um we spoke to the techu team to ask why this was potentially going on and then
然后，我们与Techu团队进行了交谈，询问为什么这可能会发生，然后
we had the aha moment oh yeah it's probably because um of octet band restream you can
我们有一个AHA的时刻哦，是的，这可能是因为您可以限制八位钟频段。
disable that so what we did is we added this extra vc parameter and this says uh don't do that just
禁用那是这样，我们添加了此额外的VC参数，这说明不这样做
give me sse i'm happy and with this i was proposing again so i knew that it was because my
给我SSE我很高兴，因此我再次提出了建议，所以我知道那是因为我
json rpc snooper was broken so now um the only variable that was left to do is remove this update
json rpc snooper被打破了，所以现在唯一要做的变量就是删除此更新
the json rpc snooper and then i have to update the image right so what i did was in my local version
JSON RPC Snooper，然后我必须正确更新图像，所以我在本地版本中所做的是
I would do, yeah, in my local Docker image, I was updating this. So whatever Pari Tosh dot json RPC
是的，在当地的Docker映像中，我正在对此进行更新。因此，无论哪种pari tosh dot json rpc
test one, and then I can run this exact same test.
测试一个，然后我可以进行完全相同的测试。
like this. And now what happens is this exact test definition that I know is broken,
像这样。现在发生的是我知道已损坏的确切测试定义，
will use this Docker image instead of what was configured in the remote repository. And I tested
将使用此Docker映像，而不是在远程存储库中配置的图像。我测试了
this extensively locally. And once it worked, I was happy with the solution. I made all the
这在本地广泛。一旦工作，我对解决方案感到满意。我做了所有的
adquisite PRs and then we consider this a resolved issue. We found something else
Adqisite PR，然后我们认为这是一个解决问题。我们找到了其他东西
with the event stream, we're still trying to figure out that something else so if
通过事件流，我们仍在尝试弄清楚其他问题，因此
someone wants a moderately difficult problem, try this out, try out this config
有人想要一个中等困难的问题，尝试一下，尝试此配置
and you will see that Teco proposes blocks but every now and then it fails
您会看到Teco提出了块，但时不时地失败了
with the proposal, just the third participant, and then go to the JSON RPC
提出建议，仅是第三名参与者，然后转到JSON RPC
snupper and figure out why it's failing and make a PR and we're very happy about
Snupper并弄清楚为什么失败并制造PR，我们对
about it and I showed you how to test the entire thing locally so you know how to reproduce it you
关于它，我向您展示了如何在本地测试整个过程，以便您知道如何重现它
know when it's not failing yeah you kind of got the entire picture of how we do prototyping and
知道什么时候没有失败，是的，您都了解了我们如何进行原型制作和
fixing none of this requires me to talk to anyone outside of myself I can test this a million times
解决这些问题都不需要我与我自己之外的任何人交谈，我可以测试一百万次
I've never written rust code in my life I was able to use different tools to understand what
我一生中从未写下生锈代码，我能够使用不同的工具来了解什么
error might have been and try out a few solutions myself without having to push any big changes
错误可能已经存在，并且自己尝试了一些解决方案，而不必推动任何重大更改
without knowing it works so that's a practical example um yeah i mean i can just run this for
不知道它有效，所以这是一个实用的例子，是的，我的意思是我可以为此而来
you if you want it'll take a while but um you can see all the steps it goes through oh well yeah and
如果您愿意，您将需要一段时间，但是您可以看到它通过的所有步骤哦，是的，是的
as you can imagine this fails immediately uh because this this image does not exist so
您可以想象，这立即失败了，因为这个图像不存在
let's switch back to normal and this will most likely work it will spin up all of my instances
让我们改回正常
it will create genesis uh i know we're already uh ahead of out of time mario is it still okay
它将创造创世纪，嗯，我知道我们已经在时间之前已经uh了
if i take a few minutes to finish this of course it's only up to you uh we don't want to you know
如果我花了几分钟才能完成此操作，那当然只取决于您，我们不想知道
take your time so if you're free it's it's okay right people are still uh uh listening and uh
花点时间，如果你有空的话，可以的人还可以，呃，呃，呃
very thankful for the experiment very excited uh it's great to see it run it is a great example by
非常感谢实验非常兴奋，很高兴看到它运行是一个很好的例子
the way uh the current issue and relevant also because last week we had um uh in this call we
uh当前问题的方式和相关性也是因为上周我们在这个电话中有UM UH
had paul from teku uh explaining uh the tech architecture so they should have an idea uh
如果来自Teku Uh的Paul解释了技术架构，所以他们应该有一个主意
So it's perfect.
所以这是完美的。
Perfect.
完美的。
So if someone wants to make a PR fixing all of our problems,
因此，如果有人想解决我们的所有问题，
we're very happy.
我们很高兴。
Awesome, awesome.
很棒，很棒。
Yeah, it might just take a bit
是的，可能只需要一点
because it also has to download the Docker images,
因为它也必须下载docker图像，所以
but hopefully it does not take too long.
但是希望这不会花太长时间。
As you can see the steps,
如您所见，
it kind of goes through the configuration.
这是通过配置进行的。
It just deploys one by one things that need to be deployed.
它只是部署需要部署的一件事。
It will fetch peering information.
它将获取对等信息。
it will set up peering as expected and I hope you also see kind of this benefit of having an
它将按照预期进行凝视，希望您也能看到有一个好处
overrideable approach if I add VC extra params I know that my validator is running with one extra
如果我添加vc额外参数，我知道我的验证器正在运行一个额外
parameter and I can test something that the other validators don't have so you can do a
参数和我可以测试其他验证者没有的东西，因此您可以执行
a lot of iterating testing this way yeah it should just be yeah creating the validators now and maybe
是的，很多迭代测试是的，现在应该是现在创建验证器，也许是
one example of uh how this looks under the hood if i do docker ps dash a it's a bunch of docker
如果我做Docker PS Dash A，这是一堆Docker
containers with tasks and you can see my els here and my cls here but i don't recommend interacting
包含任务的容器，您可以在这里看到我的EL和我的CL，但我不建议进行互动
with kurtosis that way if you wait for this to get done the kurtosis cli itself allows you to
如果您等待完成此操作，则使用Kurtosis进行这种方式，Kurtosis CLI本身可以使您能够
get all of this information in a much nicer to see way you can interact with it directly with
以更好的方式获取所有这些信息，以查看您可以直接与之互动的方式
docker nothing stops you but it will give you all of these for example urls if i was
Docker没有什么阻止您的
to go to this url it will open dora for me um so i will uh quickly just share my screen and
要转到此URL，它将为我打开Dora，所以我很快就会分享我的屏幕和
show you how DORA looks.
向您展示Dora的外观。
So this is DORA it's running on the Dineb fork with my local devnet which has three geth
因此，这是Dora，它与我的本地Devnet一起在Dineb Fork上运行，该Devnet有三个Geth
participants. You can look at the blocks, you can look at the graffiti, you can see everything,
参与者。您可以查看块，可以查看涂鸦，您可以看到一切，
you can see the validator key and the error I'm talking about essentially happens with the first
您可以看到验证器键，而我在谈论的错误本质上是第一个发生的
one, the missed block that shouldn't have been missed. And if I was to do kurtosis service logs,
第一，错过的障碍物不应该错过。如果我要做峰度服务日志，
then I specify my enclave name. And then I specify the instance I want to get logs from. So
然后我指定了我的飞地名称。然后我指定了要从中获取日志的实例。所以
please use autofill, it works really nicely. And then I want to follow the logs. And this
请使用Autofill，它非常好。然后我想遵循日志。这
is my logs from the third CL. And you can see there is some error, but that's about
是我的第三个CL的日志。您可以看到有一些错误，但这就是
Validator fee recipient, nothing else. Otherwise it looks quite okay. And it just built a block
验证者费用收件人，别无其他。否则看起来还不错。它只是建立了一个块
on slot 12. So if I wait a second, slot 12 was built by three. So that whole system works.
在插槽12上。因此，如果我等待一秒钟，则插槽12是由三个建造的。因此整个系统起作用。
and for example if I do snopper beacon 3 this is the snopper for beacon 3 and you
例如，如果我做Snopper Beacon 3这是Beacon 3的Snopper，那么您
can see all the request responses that are coming through on that on that
可以看到有关此的所有请求响应
interface and then what else is interesting well yeah just look at
接口，然后还有什么有趣的是，看看
service logs and if you ever need to know what's going on I forgot the enclave
服务日志，如果您需要知道发生了什么，我忘记了飞地
inspect command but you can inspect what is running in a running
检查命令，但您可以检查运行中正在运行的内容
enclave as well. Great yeah it's really great so you basically like
同时也是飞地。太好了，真的很棒，所以您基本上喜欢
Instead of the Docker tooling, you have this kurtosis wrapper, which gives you all the
您没有Docker工具，而是具有此峰度包装纸，它为您提供了所有
options, and it's crafted for this, it works really nicely.
选项，为此而制定，它的效果非常好。
Yeah, amazing.
是的，很棒。
I think it's a few minutes over, and I don't really want to hold you up longer, but huge
我认为已经过了几分钟了，我真的不想让您更长的时间，但是很大
thanks for going the extra mile, for giving us the demo.
感谢您为我们提供演示的额外努力。
We really appreciate it.
我们真的很感激。
I personally love all the DevOps tools, it's really fun how you go further, and we see
我个人喜欢所有的DevOps工具，这真的很有趣，您会看到
others will adjacent sniffer.
其他人会毗邻嗅探者。
There is also snatched through.
还抢走了。
There is always something
总有东西
we are working on it, but it's around.
我们正在努力，但它在附近。
So yes.
是的。
So yes, it is much for all of your work, Pari,
是的，这对您的所有工作都非常重要，Pari，
and especially for this presentation it was it was
尤其是在这个演讲中
it was a great learning experience.
这是一次很棒的学习经历。
Yeah, people are trying to the court houses.
是的，人们正在试图去法院。
They are asking some questions in the discord.
他们在不和谐中问一些问题。
If you join the discord, you can you can maybe go there
如果您加入不和谐，您可以去那里
if you have a minute, but it's still up to you.
如果您有一分钟，但这仍然取决于您。
I will show you the link later.
稍后我将向您展示链接。
But to all of you folks who've been paying attention, thank you so much.
但是，对于所有一直关注的人，都非常感谢。
I hope you hope you learned something.
希望您希望您学到一些东西。
And if you have some extra questions for Pari
如果您对Pari有一些额外的问题
or if you're trying these things, please share your results with us.
或者，如果您正在尝试这些事情，请与我们分享您的结果。
We're very thankful that you gave like very good specific examples
我们非常感谢您给出了很好的特定例子
of what people can practice, what they can try afterwards.
人们可以练习，之后可以尝试的东西。
That's it's very helpful.
这是非常有帮助的。
And yeah, and I'll see you folks on Wednesday for a talk by Piper Marianne.
是的，我会在星期三见到你们，派珀·玛丽安（Piper Marianne）进行演讲。
and we can wrap it up here.
我们可以在这里结束它。
Yeah.
是的。
Thank you very much, Pari, again.
非常感谢您，帕里。
Appreciate it.
感谢它。
You're welcome.
不客气。
See you guys.
见你们。
Bye-bye.
再见。